<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE help SYSTEM "pcc2help.dtd">
<help priority="99">
  <!-- Main TOC -->
  <page id="toc">
    <h1>PCC2 Help Table of Content</h1>
    <ul>
      <li>Startup
      <ul>
        <li><a href="pcc2:invoke">Invoking PCC2</a>;</li>
        <li><a href="config:intro">Configuration files</a>.</li>
      </ul></li>
      <li>Using
      <ul>
        <li><a href="pcc2:gamesel">Game Selection</a>;</li>
        <li><a href="pcc2:racescreen">Race Screen</a>;</li>
        <li><a href="pcc2:cscreen">Control Screen</a>;</li>
        <li><a href="pcc2:starchart">Starchart</a>;</li>
        <li><a href="pcc2:bsim">Battle Simulator</a>;</li>
        <li><a href="help">Help</a>.</li>
      </ul></li>
      <li><a href="int:intro">Script Interpreter</a>.</li>
    </ul>
  </page>


  <!-- Invoking -->
  <page id="group:invoking">
    <h1>Invocation</h1>

    <page id="pcc2:invoke">
      <h1>Invoking PCC2</h1>
      <p>PCC2 is a graphical application.
        If you have used the PCC2 Installer, it will have set up an icon for you.
        Otherwise, you will have to start it manually.
        Just starting it (double-click the program) will work, but by passing additional parameters,
        you can customize startup.
        Not counting options, The following possibilities exist:</p>
      <ul>
        <li><tt>c2ng</tt><br />
          (no player number and directory): start with a <a href="pcc2:gamesel">game chooser</a>;</li>
        <li><tt>c2ng GAMEDIR</tt><br />
          start with a <a href="pcc2:gamesel">game chooser</a> in the specified directory.</li>
      </ul>
      <p>You do not have to unpack your RST before playing.
        If you don't, PCC2 will read the RST directly, and produce a TRN directly.
        If you do unpack your turn, PCC2 will behave like a classic VGA Planets&#x2122; client and just modify <tt>.dat</tt> files;
        you will then have to run Maketurn separately.</p>
      <p>To play registered, place a <tt>fizz.bin</tt> file created by your registered client in the game directory,
        just like you do with PCC 1.x.</p>
      <p><tt>c2ng</tt> accepts some command line options as shown below,
        and honors some <a href="env">environment variables</a>.</p>
      <p>The PCC2 Installer for Windows will make a Start Menu shortcut
      which will start PCC2 with a game selector, starting at your Winplan directory.</p>

      <h2>Command-Line Options</h2>
      <ul>
        <li><tt>--bpp=<em>BITS</em></tt>: bits per pixel;</li>
        <li><tt>--fullscreen</tt>: full-screen mode (opposite of <tt>--windowed</tt>);</li>
        <li><tt>--nomousegrab</tt>: don't grab mouse pointer.
          By default, PCC2 grabs the mouse pointer in the starchart to support infinite movement.
          However, this prevents you from switching to another application while in the starchart;</li>
        <li><tt>--password=<em>PASS</em></tt>: result file password;</li>
        <li><tt>--proxy=<em>URL</em></tt>: use proxy for network access. URL can be "socks4://host:port" or "sock5://host:port";</li>
        <li><tt>--resource=<em>NAME</em></tt>: add a resource file;</li>
        <li><tt>--size=<em>WIDTHxHEIGHT</em></tt>: set screen resolution or window size;</li>
        <li><tt>--windowed</tt>: windowed mode (opposite of <tt>--fullscreen</tt>).</li>
      </ul>
    </page>

    <page id="env">
      <h1>Environment Variables</h1>
      <p>The following environment variables are evaluated by PCC2, or by the SDL library it is based upon:</p>
      <ul>
        <li><tt>SDL_VIDEODRIVER</tt>: select a video driver. Possible choices are, depending upon your version of SDL:
          <tt>x11</tt> (Unix: X11),
          <tt>dga</tt> (Unix: XFree DGA),
          <tt>fbcon</tt> (Linux: framebuffer console),
          <tt>svgalib</tt> (Unix: SVGAlib),
          <tt>aalib</tt> (ASCII art, more for fun than actually useful),
          <tt>windib</tt> (Win32: standard GDI),
          <tt>directx</tt> (Win32 DirectX).
        Normally, SDL auto-detects the best driver to use;</li>
        <!-- <li><tt>SDL_AUDIODRIVER</tt>: select an audio driver. Possible choices are, depending upon your version of SDL:
          <tt>alsa</tt> (Linux: ALSA),
          <tt>dma</tt> (Unix: OSS DMA),
          <tt>dsp</tt> (Unix: OSS standard),
          <tt>esd</tt> (Linux: Enlightened sound daemon),
          <tt>waveout</tt> (Win32: standard WaveOut),
          <tt>dsound</tt> (Win32: DirectX).
          Normally, SDL auto-detects the best driver to use;</li> -->
        <li><tt>LC_ALL</tt>, <tt>LC_MESSAGES</tt>, <tt>LANG</tt> (Unix):
          select language. PCC2 uses the first of those variables which is set.
          It should contain a two-letter language code, optionally followed by additional information ignored by PCC2.
          For example, <tt>de</tt> selects German language, like <tt>de_DE</tt>, <tt>de_AT</tt>, <tt>de_DE@utf-8</tt>, etc.;</li>
        <li><tt>HOME</tt> (Unix): your home directory.
          PCC2's <a href="config:intro">configuration directory</a>, <tt>.pcc2</tt>, goes there.</li>
      </ul>
      <p>To change environment variables permanently under Windows NT or higher,
        right-click <em>My Computer</em>, choose <em>Properties</em>, choose
        <em>Advanced</em>, choose <em>Environment Variables</em>, and add the
        variable in the <em>User Variables</em> section.
        Users of other environments put the variables into their startup or login scripts,
        such as <tt>autoexec.bat</tt> or <tt>.profile</tt>.</p>
    </page>
  </page>

  <!-- Screens -->
  <page id="group:screens">
    <h1>PCC2 Screens</h1>

    <!-- Game Selection Screen -->
    <page id="pcc2:gamesel">
      <h1>Game Selection</h1>
      <p>Welcome to PCC2 Next Generation!</p>

      <p><font color="red"><b>Note:</b> The <b>Help</b> key in most of PCC2 is <kbd>Alt-H</kbd>
        (or, where possible, <kbd>H</kbd>),
        not <kbd>F1</kbd> like in many other current desktop programs.
        <kbd>F1</kbd> will work in some screens, but not all.</font></p>

      <p>The Game Selection screen allows you to select a game from your computer, or from a server.
        On top level (labeled "[Places]"), you can either browse into your computer ("My Computer"),
        or into one of the accounts that you created.
        Use <kbd>Ins</kbd> to <a href="pcc2:addaccount">add an account</a>.</p>

      <p>To enter a directory or account, select it on the left and double-click it or press <kbd>Enter</kbd>.
        When looking at a game, available races will be shown on the right.
        Open it for <a href="pcc2:racescreen">playing</a> by double-clicking the race.
        If additional actions are available for a game, choose "Setup &amp; Actions...".</p>

      <kl>
        <ki key="Tab">Switch between fields;</ki>
        <ki key="Left">Switch to directory selector; if already there, go to parent directory;</ki>
        <ki key="Right">Switch to player selector; if not possible, enter directory;</ki>
        <ki key="Enter">On player selector: load game; otherwise like <kbd>Right</kbd>;</ki>
        <ki key="Ins"><a href="pcc2:addaccount">Add account</a>;</ki>
        <ki key="U"><a href="pcc2:unpack">Unpack result files</a>;</ki>
        <ki key="M">Make turn files;</ki>
        <ki key="S"><a href="pcc2:sweep">Clean up directory (sweep)</a>;</ki>
        <ki key="F5"><a href="pcc2:plugins">Plugin Manager</a>;</ki>
        <ki key="ESC">Exit.</ki>
      </kl>

      <p>When a game contains game data, <kbd>Enter</kbd> and <kbd>Right</kbd> will not browse its subdirectories,
        but switch to the game selector instead.
        Normally, game directories do not contain other game directories.
        Use the <em>Change into this folder</em> item at the bottom of the player list
        to browse subdirectories.</p>

        <!-- FIXME: describe additional actions -->

      <h2>Reference</h2>
      <dl>
        <di term="See also:"> <a href="toc">Table of Content</a>, <a href="pcc2:invoke">Invoking PCC2</a>.</di>
      </dl>
    </page>

    <page id="pcc2:addaccount">
      <h1>Add Account</h1>
      <p>PCC2 supports directly talking to hosting servers.
        To do so, you need to tell it your login data.
        You will then be able to browse your games on the server, using PCC2.</p>

      <p>To define an account, enter your user name and choose the server type (PlanetsCentral or planets.nu).
        The account will now appear on the top level of the <a href="pcc2:gamesel">Game Selection screen</a>.</p>

      <h2>Reference</h2>
      <dl>
        <di term="Keys:"><kbd>Ins</kbd> from <a href="pcc2:gamesel">PCC2 Game Selection</a>.</di>
      </dl>
    </page>

    <page id="pcc2:gamedirsetup">
      <h1>Game Directory Setup</h1>

      <p>PCC2 requires a directory to store local data, for example, configuration and history (starchart database).
        When you open a game that has no suitable directory assigned, PCC2 will ask you to provide one.</p>

      <p>Choose between the following possibilities:</p>
      <dl>
        <di term="Automatic"> PCC2 will automatically create a directory in your profile directory
          (<tt>$HOME/.pcc2/games</tt>, <tt>C:\Users\User\AppData\Roaming\PCC2</tt>).
          If you're not planning to use anything other than PCC2, that is a good choice;</di>
        <di term="Manual"> PCC2 will ask you to choose a directory.
          The dialog allows you to pick an existing directory, or create a new one.
          The directory should be empty to not create conflicts with the new data stored by PCC2.
          This is a good choice if you plan to use software other than PCC2 (e.g. VPA, EchoView) as well,
          and need to know exactly how your directory structure is set up;</di>
        <di term="None"> PCC2 will not use a local directory.
          The game will be opened read-only, no data will be stored locally.
          This is a good choice if you only want to look at the game data (e.g. data of a game that's long over).</di>
      </dl>

      <h2>Reference</h2>
      <dl>
        <di term="See also:"> <a href="pcc2:gamesel">PCC2 Game Selection</a>.</di>
      </dl>
    </page>

    <!-- Unpack Screen -->
    <page id="pcc2:unpack">
      <h1>Unpack</h1>

      <p>With classic VGA Planets, you receive result (*.rst) files from your host, and send turn (*.trn) files to your host.
        PCC2 will be able to play directly with those files.
        However, many traditional programs require the files to be unpacked before they can be used.</p>

      <p>The Unpack function displays a list of result files found.
        Select those you want to unpack.
        When you start from a game directory containing unpacked data,
        the results corresponding to the unpacked data will be highlighted by default.</p>

      <p>Normally, you use the Unpack function at the beginning of a turn.
        If you Unpack mid-turn, your game will be reset to the beginning of the turn, undoing all your commands.
        If you have matching turn files, PCC2 will by default apply these turn files as well,
        to return you to the state when you last ran Maketurn.</p>

      <kl>
        <ki key="&#x2191;, &#x2193;">Move around;</ki>
        <ki key="Space">Toggle;</ki>
        <ki key="1..9, A, B">Toggle that race;</ki>
        <ki key="*">Mark/unmark all;</ki>
        <ki key="Alt-A">Toggle "Apply turn files" option;</ki>
        <!-- <ki key="T"><a href="pcc2:resultattachments">Unpack attachments</a></ki> -->
        <ki key="Enter">Unpack all selected players;</ki>
        <ki key="ESC">Cancel.</ki>
      </kl>

      <p>You can also use the command line utility <tt>c2unpack</tt> to unpack result files.</p>

      <h2>Reference</h2>
      <dl>
        <di term="Keys:"> <kbd>U</kbd> from <a href="pcc2:gamesel">Game Selection</a>, and on directory menu.</di>
      </dl>
    </page>

    <!-- Sweep Screen -->
    <page id="pcc2:sweep">
      <h1>Clean Up Directory (Sweep)</h1>

      <p>The <em>Sweep</em> function can be used to clean up game directories,
        for example, when you accidentally unpacked game files, or otherwise got your files mixed up.</p>

      <p>Select the player slots you you want to delete.
        When you start from a game directory containing turn conflicts, the older files will start selected.</p>

      <kl>
        <ki key="&#x2191;, &#x2193;">Move around;</ki>
        <ki key="Space">Toggle;</ki>
        <ki key="1..9, A, B">Toggle that race;</ki>
        <ki key="Alt-D">Toggle "Delete database files" option.
          With this option enabled, this function also deletes files that are usually kept longer, such as <tt>chartX.cc</tt>, PCC's history file.
          With this option disabled, only per-turn files are deleted, such as <tt>bdataX.dat</tt>.
          The Sweep function will never delete result or turn files;</ki>
        <ki key="*">Mark/unmark all;</ki>
        <ki key="Enter">Sweep;</ki>
        <ki key="ESC">Cancel.</ki>
      </kl>

      <p>You can also use the command line utility <tt>c2sweep</tt> to clean game directories.</p>

      <h2>Reference</h2>
      <dl>
        <di term="Keys:"> <kbd>S</kbd> from <a href="pcc2:gamesel">Game Selection</a>, and on directory menu.</di>
      </dl>
    </page>

    <!-- Plugin Manager -->
    <page id="pcc2:plugins">
      <h1>Plugins</h1>
      <p>Plugins provide additional functionality or artwork for PCC2.
        This screen displays all installed plugins and allows you to add or remove some.</p>
      <kl>
        <ki key="&#x2191;, &#x2193;">Move around;</ki>
        <ki key="Ins">Add (install) a new plugin;</ki>
        <ki key="Del">Remove (uninstall) a plugin;</ki>
        <ki key="ESC">Close window.</ki>
      </kl>

      <h2>Plugin Installation (Ins)</h2>

      <p>A plugin typically consists of one or more files, plus an accompanying plugin description in the form of a <tt>*.c2p</tt> file.
        All these files can be compressed to a single <tt>*.c2z</tt> (or <tt>*.zip</tt>) file.
        When you want to install a plugin, PCC2 will ask you for the <tt>*.c2p</tt> or <tt>*.c2z</tt> file.</p>

      <p>If you just have a <tt>*.res</tt> or <tt>*.q</tt> file you want loaded, you can also directly install that.</p>

      <p>After you choose a file, PCC2 will check preconditions and ask you for confirmation before installing the plugin.
        Installing copies the plugin into your user profile directory;
        the original data is not needed anymore after installation.</p>

      <h2>Plugin Uninstallation (Del)</h2>

      <p>When you select a plugin for uninstallation, PCC2 will check preconditions
        and ask you for confirmation before uninstalling the plugin.</p>

      <h2>Notes</h2>

      <p>After you uninstall a plugin, some remains of it may remain still active until you exit PCC2.
        That's why PCC2 will remind you to restart after a plugin has been removed or updated.</p>
        <p>There also is a command-line utility <tt>c2plugin</tt> you can use to manage plugins.
        When you have installed PCC2 for Windows using the installer,
        launching a <tt>*.c2z</tt> or <tt>*.c2p</tt> file (by double-clicking in Explorer, or from a web browser) will directly install the plugin.</p>

      <h2>Reference</h2>
      <dl>
        <di term="Keys:"> <kbd>F5</kbd> from <a href="pcc2:gamesel">PCC2 Game Selection</a>.</di>
      </dl>
    </page>

    <!-- FIXME: pcc2:resultattachments -->

    <!-- Race Screen -->
    <page id="pcc2:racescreen">
      <h1>Race Screen</h1>
      <p>This screen is the central point of your empire.</p>
      <kl>
        <ki key="F1"><a href="pcc2:unitsel">Ship selector</a>,   then <a href="pcc2:shipscreen">ship screen</a>;</ki>
        <ki key="F2"><a href="pcc2:unitsel">Planet selector</a>, then <a href="pcc2:planetscreen">planet screen</a>;</ki>
        <ki key="F3"><a href="pcc2:unitsel">Base selector</a>,   then <a href="pcc2:basescreen">base screen</a>;</ki>
        <ki key="F4"><a href="pcc2:starchart">Starchart</a>;</ki>
        <ki key="F6"><a href="pcc2:historyselect">Choose ship</a>, then <a href="pcc2:historyscreen">Starship History</a>;</ki>
        <ki key="F7"><a href="pcc2:search">Search object</a>;</ki>
        <ki key="F10"><a href="pcc2:fleetscreen">Fleet screen</a>;</ki>
        <ki key="A"><a href="pcc2:allies">Alliances</a>;</ki>
        <ki key="B"><a href="pcc2:bsim">Battle simulator</a>;</ki>
        <ki key="G"><a href="pcc2:globact">Global actions</a>;</ki>
        <ki key="I"><a href="pcc2:imperial">Imperial Statistics</a>;</ki>
        <ki key="M"><a href="pcc2:msgin">Read messages</a>;</ki>
        <ki key="S"><a href="pcc2:scores">Score display</a>;</ki>
        <ki key="T"><a href="pcc2:teams">Team settings</a>;</ki>
        <ki key="V"><a href="pcc2:vcr">Watch VCRs</a>;</ki>
        <ki key="W"><a href="pcc2:msgout">Write/revise messages</a>;</ki>
        <ki key="Shift-A"><a href="pcc2:almanac">Universe Almanac</a> (specification browser);</ki>
        <ki key="Alt-&#x2191;">Show previous turn;</ki>
        <ki key="Alt-&#x2193;">Show next turn;</ki>
        <ki key="Alt-C">Open <a href="pcc2:console">console</a>;</ki>
        <ki key="Alt-E"><a href="pcc2:auxcmds">Edit auxiliary commands</a>;</ki>
        <ki key="Alt-K"><a href="pcc2:keymap">Keymap debugger</a>;</ki>
        <ki key="Alt-M">View file using <a href="pcc2:msgin">message viewer</a>;</ki>
        <ki key="Alt-N">Open <a href="pcc2:notify">Notification messages</a>;</ki>
        <ki key="Alt-Q">Open <a href="pcc2:processmgr">Process Manager</a>;</ki>
        <ki key="Alt-U">Show <tt>util.dat</tt> using <a href="pcc2:msgin">message viewer</a>;</ki>
        <ki key="Alt-.">Open <a href="pcc2:selectionmgr">selection manager</a>;</ki>
        <ki key="Alt-Left, Alt-Right">Next/previous selection layer;</ki>
        <ki key="Backspace">Go to previous screen;</ki>
        <ki key="Alt-Backspace">Show list of previous screens;</ki>
        <ki key="Ctrl-O"><a href="pcc2:settings">Settings</a>;</ki>
        <ki key="Ctrl-S">Save game without exiting;</ki>
        <ki key="ESC">Save and exit.</ki>
      </kl>
      <h2>Reference</h2>
      <dl class="compact">
        <di term="Keys:"> <kbd>ESC</kbd> from most screens;</di>
        <di term="Keymap:"> <a href="int:name:racescreen">RaceScreen</a>;</di>
        <di term="Script context:"> global context.</di>
      </dl>
    </page>

    <!-- Settings screen -->
    <page id="pcc2:settings">
      <h1>Settings</h1>
      <p>This dialog has three pages:</p>
      <dl>
        <di term="Game Settings"> game options. These options are configured in the host
          and take effect the next turn.
          This includes the option to set a <em>result file password</em> or <em>rename your race</em>,
          if allowed;</di>
        <di term="Options"> most of PCC's options, grouped in a user-friendly way, with user-friendly editors.
          Most users use this part;</di>
        <di term="Configuration File"> all of PCC's options, in the form as they appear in <tt><a href="config:pcc2ini">pcc2.ini</a></tt> files.
          This part is for experienced users only.</di>
      </dl>

      <h2>Keys</h2>
      <kl>
        <ki key="Enter">edit the currently-selected option;</ki>
        <ki key="&#x2191;, &#x2193;">move around;</ki>
        <ki key="Tab">switch page;</ki>
        <ki key="S">choose where the settings is stored:
        <ul>
          <li>in the Game configuration file (<tt>pcc2.ini</tt> in the game directory);</li>
          <li>in the User configuration file (<tt><a href="config:pcc2ini">pcc2.ini</a></tt> in your <a href="config:intro">home directory/user profile directory</a>).</li>
        </ul></ki>
        <ki key="Space">on the <em>Options</em> page: open a subtree;</ki>
        <ki key="ESC">Close this dialog.</ki>
      </kl>
      <h2>Reference</h2>
      <dl>
        <di term="Keys:"> <kbd>Ctrl-O</kbd> on <a href="pcc2:racescreen">race screen</a>;</di>
        <di term="See also:"> <a href="pcc2:settings:backup">Backup settings</a>.</di>
      </dl>
    </page>

    <!-- Settings - Backup -->
    <page id="pcc2:settings:backup">
      <h1>Backup Settings</h1>
      <p>PCC2 can create backups of game files on various occasions.</p>

      <p>It offers choice between three settings:</p>
      <dl>
        <di term="disabled"> no backups will be made;</di>
        <di term="enabled"> the file will be created in a directory <tt>backups</tt> within the game directory;</di>
        <di term="custom"> you can enter a custom file name template.</di>
      </dl>

      <p>Internally, the "enabled" setting is just a default file name template.
        File name templates are file names that can contain the following placeholders:</p>
      <dl>
        <di term="%d"> the game directory.
        If the template starts with this placeholder, it will be replaced by the complete directory name.
        If the placeholder appears in the middle of the template, it will be replaced by the final component of the
        directory name;</di>
        <di term="%p"> the player number from 1..11;</di>
        <di term="%t"> the turn number with three digits, 001..999;</di>
        <di term="%%"> a literal percent sign.</di>
      </dl>
      <p>If the name refers to a non-existing directory, the directory will be created.</p>

      <h2>Examples</h2>

      <p>Assuming you're playing player 7 in <tt>c:\games\first</tt>, and it's turn 42.
      This would yield the following expansions:</p>
      <ul>
        <li><tt>%d\backups\turn%p.%t</tt> (default)<br />
          &#x2192; <tt>c:\games\first\backups\turn7.042</tt></li>
        <li><tt>c:\backups\%d\turn%p.%t</tt><br />
          &#x2192; <tt>c:\backups\first\turn7.042</tt></li>
      </ul>

      <h2>Reference</h2>
      <dl>
        <di term="Keys:"> backup options on <a href="pcc2:settings">settings dialog</a></di>
      </dl>
    </page>

    <!-- Unit selector (ship/planet/base) -->
    <page id="pcc2:unitsel">
      <h1>Unit selector</h1>

      <p>Use this window to select a unit.
        Usually this is used to enter a <a href="pcc2:cscreen">control screen</a>.</p>
      <kl>
        <ki key="&#x2191;, &#x2193;">Browse through objects;</ki>
        <ki key="Home, End">Go to first&#47;last object;</ki>
        <ki key="Tab">Go to next object at this place;</ki>
        <ki key="Shift-Tab">Go to previous object at this place;</ki>
        <ki key="Ctrl">(with one of the browsing keys) limit browsing to marked objects;</ki>
        <ki key=".">Mark/unmark current object;</ki>
        <ki key="Enter">Select object.</ki>
      </kl>

      <h2>Reference</h2>
      <dl>
        <di term="Keys:"> <kbd>F1</kbd>, <kbd>F2</kbd>, <kbd>F3</kbd> or <kbd>F10</kbd> almost everywhere;</di>
        <di term="Keymap:">
          <a href="int:name:shipselectiondialog">ShipSelectionDialog</a>,
          <a href="int:name:planetselectiondialog">PlanetSelectionDialog</a>,
          <a href="int:name:baseselectiondialog">BaseSelectionDialog</a>,
          <a href="int:name:fleetselectiondialog">FleetSelectionDialog</a>;
        </di>
        <di term="Related command:"> <a href="int:name:ui.chooseobject">UI.ChooseObject</a>;</di>
        <di term="See also:">
          <a href="pcc2:shipscreen">Ship Screen</a>,
          <a href="pcc2:planetscreen">Planet Screen</a>,
          <a href="pcc2:basescreen">Starbase Screen</a>,
          <a href="pcc2:fleetscreen">Fleet Screen</a>.
        </di>
      </dl>
    </page>

    <!-- History ship selector -->
    <page id="pcc2:historyselect">
      <h1>History Ship Selection</h1>
      <p>The dialog displays all ships of a certain kind in a list.
        Choose one to get to the <a href="pcc2:historyscreen">Ship History Screen</a>.</p>
      <kl>
        <ki key="D">Choose display filter:
          <ul>
            <li>All ships: all ships you've ever seen;</li>
            <li>Ships near (X,Y): all ships near the given position (only available when you call this dialog from the <a href="pcc2:starchart">starchart</a> or a <a href="pcc2:cscreen">control screen</a>);</li>
            <li>Ships exactly at (X,Y): all ships exactly at the given position (same restriction as "Ships near");</li>
            <li>Foreign ships: all ships you do not own;</li>
            <li>Team ships: all your ships and ships of your team-mates (only when <a href="pcc2:teams">teams</a> configured);</li>
            <li>Enemy ships: all ships of enemy teams (only when <a href="pcc2:teams">teams</a> configured);</li>
            <li>Own ships: all your ships.</li>
          </ul>
        </ki>
      </kl>
      <h2>Reference</h2>
      <dl>
        <di term="Keys:"> <kbd>F6</kbd> almost everywhere</di>
        <di term="Related command:"> <a href="int:name:ui.chooseobject">UI.ChooseObject</a></di>
        <di term="See also:"><a href="pcc2:historyscreen">Ship History Screen</a></di>
      </dl>
    </page>

    <!-- Control screen (referenced by actual control screens) -->
    <page id="pcc2:cscreen">
      <h1>Control Screen</h1>
      <p>Control screens allow you to inspect and control individual units.
        All control screens support similar keys.</p>

      <kl>
        <ki key="PgUp, PgDn">Browse (with <kbd>Ctrl</kbd>: only marked units);</ki>
        <ki key=".">Mark&#47;unmark unit;</ki>
        <ki key="F1">Choose ship;</ki>
        <ki key="F2">Choose planet;</ki>
        <ki key="F3, F8">Choose base;</ki>
        <ki key="F4">Go to starchart;</ki>
        <ki key="F6"><a href="pcc2:historyscreen">Starship History</a>;</ki>
        <ki key="F10">Choose fleet;</ki>
        <ki key="Shift-F1, Shift-F2, Shift-F3, Shift-F4, Shift-F8">Go to ship&#47;planet&#47;base&#47;starchart location at this point;</ki>
        <ki key="Ctrl-F1, Ctrl-F2, Ctrl-F3, Ctrl-F4, Ctrl-F8">Go to ship&#47;planet&#47;base&#47;starchart location at other end of scanner;</ki>
        <ki key="X">Go to unit at other end of scanner;</ki>
        <ki key="F5, Shift-F5"><a href="pcc2:envscreen">Information about planet</a> here;</ki>
        <ki key="Ctrl-F5"><a href="pcc2:envscreen">Information about planet</a> at other end of scanner;</ki>
        <ki key="F7"><a href="pcc2:search">Search object</a>;</ki>
        <ki key="Ctrl-H"><a href="pcc2:search">Search objects</a> at this location;</ki>
        <ki key="F9">Edit this unit's comment;</ki>
        <ki key="Shift-F9">Edit comment of planet here;</ki>
        <ki key="Ctrl-F9">Edit comment of planet at other end of scanner;</ki>
        <ki key="L"><a href="pcc2:listship">List ships</a> at other end of scanner;</ki>
        <ki key="Shift-L"><a href="pcc2:listship">List ships</a> here;</ki>
        <ki key="Ctrl-N"><a href="pcc2:listship">List ships</a> that will be here next turn;</ki>
        <ki key="Shift-M">Show <a href="pcc2:msgin">subspace messages</a> from this unit;</ki>
        <ki key="Y">Enable keyboard-move-scanner mode. Move scanner around with arrows, exit with <kbd>ESC</kbd>;</ki>
        <ki key="Backspace">Go to previous screen;</ki>
        <ki key="Alt-Backspace">Show list of previous screens;</ki>
        <ki key="Ins">Add unit to battle simulation;</ki>
        <ki key="Alt-C">Show <a href="pcc2:console">console</a>;</ki>
        <ki key="Alt-Q">Open <a href="pcc2:processmgr">Process Manager</a>;</ki>
        <ki key="Alt-K"><a href="pcc2:keymap">Keymap debugger</a>;</ki>
        <ki key="Alt-.">Open <a href="pcc2:selectionmgr">Selection manager</a>;</ki>
        <ki key="Alt-Left, Alt-Right">Next/previous selection layer;</ki>
        <ki key="Alt-R"><a href="pcc2:reset">Reset current location</a> (undo);</ki>
        <ki key="Enter">Toggle between regular control screen and <a href="pcc2:taskscreen">auto task screen</a>;</ki>
        <ki key="ESC">Go to <a href="pcc2:racescreen">race screen</a>.</ki>
      </kl>

      <p>You can use <kbd>Ctrl-Alt</kbd>+letter to toggle starchart options,
        e.g. <kbd>Ctrl-Alt-M</kbd> to toggle display of minefields.
        See <a href="pcc2:starchart">Starchart, section "Option Toggles"</a> for details.</p>

      <h2>Visual Elements</h2>
      <ul>
        <li>The top line on the left contains the name of the unit. If is followed by a flag icon if there are messages from the unit that can be read using <kbd>Shift-M</kbd>;</li>
        <li>The second line contains brief information about the kind of this unit (e.g. the ship type);</li>
        <li>The following block has function buttons for the major areas (<kbd>F1</kbd> etc.), and an image of the unit in the center.
        <ul>
          <li>The image has a yellow frame if the unit is selected (<kbd>.</kbd>);</li>
          <li>The "Auto" button has a green frame if the unit has an auto task, and a yellow frame if some other script is running on it;</li>
        </ul></li>
        <li>A map of the unit's surroundings appears on the right.
          You can click into it, or activate keyboard-move-scanner mode using <kbd>Y</kbd>.
          The scanner result (name of the unit you're pointing at) is shown below the map).</li>
      </ul>

      <h2>Reference</h2>
      <dl>
        <di term="Keys:"> <kbd>F1</kbd>, <kbd>F2</kbd>, <kbd>F3</kbd> or <kbd>F10</kbd> almost everywhere,
          or follow a link in <a href="pcc2:imperial">Imperial Statistics</a> or <a href="pcc2:search">Search</a>;</di>
        <di term="Related command:"> <a href="int:name:ui.gotoscreen">UI.GotoScreen</a>;</di>
        <di term="Keymap:"> <a href="int:name:controlscreen">ControlScreen</a> (extended by actual control screen's keymap);</di>
        <di term="Script context:"> respective unit;</di>
        <di term="See also:">
          <a href="pcc2:shipscreen">Ship Screen</a>,
          <a href="pcc2:planetscreen">Planet Screen</a>,
          <a href="pcc2:basescreen">Starbase Screen</a>,
          <a href="pcc2:fleetscreen">Fleet Screen</a>.
        </di>
      </dl>
    </page>

    <!-- Auto Task Screen -->
    <page id="pcc2:taskscreen">
      <h1>Auto Task Screen</h1>

      <p>PCC2 allows you to define give commands in advance.
        For example, if you want a ship to move to planet #1, then to planet #2, then to planet #3,
        you can define this route in advance using an Auto Task.</p>

      <p>Auto Tasks are scripts.
        Each line in the script is a command that may take multiple turns to execute, such as a
        <tt>MoveTo</tt> command for a ship, or a <tt>EnqueueShip</tt> command for a starbase.
        The Auto Task Screen displays the current status and lets you edit the script.</p>

      <p>The red triangle displays the current command; it is hollow when the command already started executing and solid when it hasn't.</p>

      <p>While you edit the task, it is stopped.
        It will run when you leave the auto task screen or switch to another object.</p>

      <p>When an auto task finishes (runs off its end), it is automatically removed.</p>

      <p>Auto tasks can produce messages (using the <a href="int:name:notify">Notify</a> command or by running into a problem).
        Such messages are shown in the <a href="pcc2:notify">Notification</a> dialog when you start PCC2.
        The message currently holding up this task is also shown on the auto task screen.
        When you fix the problem, you can confirm the message directly from here using <kbd>M</kbd>.</p>

      <p>The following keys are supported in addition to <a href="pcc2:cscreen">Control Screen</a> keys.</p>

      <kl>
        <ki key="Ins">Insert a command before the current line;</ki>
        <ki key="Space">Edit current command;</ki>
        <ki key="Del">Delete current command;</ki>
        <ki key="Ctrl-Del">Delete all commands;</ki>
        <ki key="%, K">Disable/enable a command temporarily (comment it out);</ki>
        <ki key="Ctrl-N">Set next command to execute;</ki>
        <ki key="1..4">Depending on actual screen, insert commands;</ki>
        <ki key="M">Confirm <a href="pcc2:notify">Notification Message</a> produced by this task (cause task to continue);</ki>
        <ki key="Ctrl-S">Save task as text file;</ki>
        <ki key="Ctrl-R">Load task from text file (insert commands at cursor);</ki>
        <ki key="Enter">Go to <a href="pcc2:cscreen">control screen</a>.</ki>
      </kl>

      <h2>Reference</h2>
      <dl>
        <di term="Keys:"> <kbd>Enter</kbd> from
          <a href="pcc2:shipscreen">ship</a>, <a href="pcc2:planetscreen">planet</a>, or
          <a href="pcc2:basescreen">starbase</a> screen;</di>
        <di term="Related command:"> <a href="int:name:ui.gotoscreen">UI.GotoScreen</a>;</di>
        <di term="Keymap:"> <a href="int:name:autotaskscreen">AutoTaskScreen</a>;</di>
        <di term="Script context:"> respective unit.</di>
      </dl>
    </page>

    <!-- Ship screen -->
    <page id="pcc2:shipscreen">
      <h1>Ship Screen</h1>

      <p>This screen allows you to control your ships.
        The following keys are supported in addition to <a href="pcc2:cscreen">Control Screen</a> keys.</p>

      <kl>
        <ki key="N">Change ship's name;</ki>
        <ki key="M">Change ship's mission;</ki>
        <ki key="E">Change ship's primary enemy;</ki>
        <ki key="A">Change ship's waypoint using <a href="pcc2:navchart">Navigation Chart</a>;</ki>
        <ki key="C"><a href="pcc2:cargo">Cargo transfer</a>;</ki>
        <ki key="D"><a href="pcc2:multicargo">Multi-ship cargo transfer</a>;</ki>
        <ki key="B">Open menu listing starbase commands applicable to this ship;</ki>
        <ki key="R">Allow&#47;forbid&#47;drop remote control for this ship (PHost feature);</ki>
        <ki key="G">Give ship away (PHost feature);</ki>
        <ki key="S">Show ship <a href="pcc2:specsheet">specification sheet</a>;</ki>
        <ki key="Q">Explain ship predictions. Tells you what missions and orders were considered for computing the fuel usage;</ki>
        <ki key="Ctrl-J">Review Jettison order;</ki>
        <ki key="Ctrl-S">Review transfer-to-enemy-ship order;</ki>
        <ki key="Ctrl-P">Review unload-to-planet order;</ki>
        <ki key="Ctrl-F">Make ship's friendly code the same as the friendly code of the planet it's orbiting;</ki>
        <ki key="Ctrl-N"><a href="pcc2:listship">List ships</a> that will be at the same position as this ship next turn. Also places the scanner at the predicted new position;</ki>
        <ki key="U">Cargo transfer to planet;</ki>
        <ki key="F">Change ship's <a href="pcc2:fcode">friendly code</a>;</ki>
        <ki key="W">Change ship's warp speed. On the warp speed dialog, type a number to set that warp factor, or <kbd>Y</kbd> to enable the Hyperdrive on ships that have one;</ki>
        <ki key="Ctrl-W">Change ship's waypoint to match the scanner;</ki>
        <ki key="Ctrl-Z">Clear ship's waypoint;</ki>
        <ki key="Ctrl-I">Go to ship whose Id is in this ship's mission's Intercept parameter (i.e. go to ship we're intercepting);</ki>
        <ki key="Alt-I"><a href="pcc2:search">Search</a> ships that have our Id as Intercept parameter (i.e. find ships intercepting us);</ki>
        <ki key="Ctrl-T">Go to ship whose Id is in this ship's mission's Tow parameter (i.e. go to ship we're towing);</ki>
        <ki key="Alt-T"><a href="pcc2:search">Search</a> ships that have our Id as Tow parameter (i.e. find ships towing us);</ki>
        <ki key="Ctrl-M">Go to ship we are chunneling to;</ki>
        <ki key="Alt-M"><a href="pcc2:search">Search</a> ships that are chunneling to us;</ki>
        <ki key="Tab">Cycle through ships at this place. With <kbd>Ctrl</kbd>: marked ships only. With <kbd>Shift</kbd>: backward;</ki>
        <ki key="F10">Fleet menu: (only applicable items will be displayed)
        <dl>
          <di term="Fleet screen">Go to <a href="pcc2:fleetscreen">Fleet Screen</a>;</di>
          <di term="Start new fleet">Make this ship the leader of a new fleet;</di>
          <di term="Join a fleet">Make this ship member of an existing fleet;</di>
          <di term="Leave fleet">Remove this ship from its fleet;</di>
          <di term="Go to fleet leader">Go to the fleet leader's ship screen;</di>
          <di term="Add all to fleet">If this ship isn't yet member of a fleet, make it leader of a new one. Then add all other ships at this place to the fleet;</di>
        </dl>
        </ki>
        <ki key="Shift-F10">Same as "Join a fleet" or "Go to fleet screen", whichever is applicable.</ki>
      </kl>

      <p>The "R" button will only appear if your game supports the Remote Control functionality
        (see <tt>pconfig.src</tt>).
        It will have a red frame if this ship's remote control is forbidden,
        a green frame if this is a remote-controlled ship (or you are applying for remote control),
        and a yellow frame if this is a remote-controlled ship you're giving back to its owner.</p>

      <p>The "G" button will only appear if your game supports the Give Ship functionality.
        It will have a yellow frame when you have given an order to give the ship away.</p>

      <p>The "F10" button will have a green frame if this ship is leader of a fleet, a red frame if it is a member.</p>

      <p>To change a ship's waypoint, double-click into the starchart.
        Alternatively, use the <a href="pcc2:navchart">Navigation Chart</a> (<kbd>A</kbd>),
        which also allows you to set up a Chunnel or Hyperjump on capable ships.</p>

      <h2>Reference</h2>
      <dl>
        <di term="Keys:"> <kbd>F1</kbd> from almost everywhere;</di>
        <di term="Related command:"> <a href="int:name:ui.gotoscreen">UI.GotoScreen</a>;</di>
        <di term="Keymap:"> <a href="int:name:shipscreen">ShipScreen</a>;</di>
        <di term="Script context:"> <a href="int:name:ship:context">Ship()</a>.</di>
      </dl>
    </page>

    <!-- Ship Task screen -->
    <page id="pcc2:shiptaskscreen">
      <h1>Ship Task Screen</h1>

      <p>This screen supports allows defining an Auto Task for a ship.
        Typically, ship auto tasks define multi-turn waypoints.
        The following keys are supported in addition to <a href="pcc2:taskscreen">Auto Task Screen</a> keys.</p>

      <kl>
        <ki key="A">Create <tt>MoveTo</tt> command using the <a href="pcc2:navchart">Navigation Chart</a>;</ki>
        <ki key="Ctrl-W">Create <tt>MoveTo</tt> command for the scanner target (same as double-click into scanner chart).</ki>
        <ki key="C, U"><a href="pcc2:cargo">Cargo transfer</a></ki>
        <ki key="G">Go to <a href="pcc2:starchart">starchart</a> showing the place the ship will be after the current command.</ki>
        <ki key="W">Change ship's warp speed.</ki>
        <ki key="O">Options that affect prediction and display:
        <ul>
          <li>Predict to cursor/to end (also use <kbd>E</kbd> to toggle).</li>
          <li>Show turn distances (also use <kbd>D</kbd> to toggle).</li>
        </ul></ki>
      </kl>

      <p>To define a waypoint, double-click into the map.
        Alternatively, use the <a href="pcc2:navchart">Navigation Chart</a> (<kbd>A</kbd>).</p>

      <h2>Ship Task Commands</h2>
      <ul>
        <li>Movement Commands
        <ul>
          <li><tt>MoveTo</tt>: set waypoint and move ship there;</li>
          <li><tt>MoveTowards</tt>: set waypoint and move for one turn (this may stop in mid-space!);</li>
          <li><tt>SetSpeed</tt>: set warp speed;</li>
          <li><tt>SetWaypoint</tt>: set waypoint, but do not move yet (ship will move during later <tt>WaitOneTurn</tt> commands, maybe.</li>
        </ul></li>
        <li>Cargo Commands: <tt>CargoUnload</tt>, <tt>CargoUpload</tt>.
          PCC2 will ask for a cargo type and create a command which transfers everything of that type.
          You can edit the command using <kbd>Space</kbd> to fit your needs;</li>
        <li>Mission Commands: <tt>SetEnemy</tt>, <tt>SetFCode</tt>, <tt>SetMission</tt>: self-explanatory;</li>
        <li>Miscellaneous Commands:
        <ul>
          <li><tt>Notify</tt>: generate a <a href="pcc2:notify">message</a> and wait until you confirm it; use this to send reminders into the future (like "have reached waypoint, refuel me");</li>
          <li><tt>SetComment</tt>: change ship comment;</li>
          <li><tt>SetName</tt>: change ship name;</li>
          <li><tt>WaitOneTurn</tt>: wait one turn, performing whatever orders that were given before;</li>
          <li><tt>Restart</tt>: restart auto task from the beginning.</li>
        </ul></li>
      </ul>

      <h2>Reference</h2>
      <dl>
        <di term="Keys:"> <kbd>Enter</kbd> from <a href="pcc2:shipscreen">ship screen</a>;</di>
        <di term="Related command:"> <a href="int:name:ui.gotoscreen">UI.GotoScreen</a>;</di>
        <di term="Keymap:"> <a href="int:name:autotaskscreen">AutoTaskScreen</a>;</di>
        <di term="Script context:"> <a href="int:name:ship:context">Ship()</a>.</di>
      </dl>
    </page>

    <!-- Planet screen -->
    <page id="pcc2:planetscreen">
      <h1>Planet Screen</h1>

      <p>This screen allows you to control your planets.
        The following keys are supported in addition to <a href="pcc2:cscreen">Control Screen</a> keys.</p>

      <kl>
        <ki key="B, D, M"><a href="pcc2:buildings">Build structures (factories, mines, defense)</a>;</ki>
        <ki key="S"><a href="pcc2:sellsup">Sell supplies</a>;</ki>
        <ki key="Ctrl-S">Undo sell supplies;</ki>
        <ki key="T"><a href="pcc2:taxes">Taxes</a>;</ki>
        <ki key="G">Give planet away (PHost feature);</ki>
        <ki key="I">Send information about this planet to another player.
          Depending on host version/configuration, you can send current information (VPA data transmission),
          or next-turn information (PHost "show" command);</ki>
        <ki key="F8">Go to starbase if any, otherwise build one.</ki>
      </kl>

      <p>The "G" button will only appear if your game supports the Give Planet functionality.
        It will have a yellow frame when you have given an order to give the planet away.</p>

      <h2>Reference</h2>
      <dl>
        <di term="Keys:"> <kbd>F2</kbd> from almost everywhere;</di>
        <di term="Related command:"> <a href="int:name:ui.gotoscreen">UI.GotoScreen</a>;</di>
        <di term="Keymap:"> <a href="int:name:planetscreen">PlanetScreen</a>;</di>
        <di term="Script context:"> <a href="int:name:planet:context">Planet()</a>.</di>
      </dl>
    </page>

    <!-- Planet Task screen -->
    <page id="pcc2:planettaskscreen">
      <h1>Planet Task Screen</h1>

      <p>This screen supports allows defining an Auto Task for a planet.
        You can use the <a href="pcc2:taskscreen">Auto Task Screen</a> keys.</p>

      <h2>Planet Task Commands</h2>
      <ul>
        <li>Order Commands:
        <ul>
          <li><tt>SetFCode</tt>: self-explanatory;</li>
        </ul></li>
        <li>Cargo Commands: <tt>CargoUnloadAllShips</tt>: unload Tritanium, Molybdenum, Duranium, colonists, supplies, and cash from all ships in orbit of this planet.
          You can edit the command using <kbd>Space</kbd> to fit your needs;</li>
        <li>Miscellaneous Commands:
        <ul>
          <li><tt>Notify</tt>: generate a <a href="pcc2:notify">message</a> and wait until you confirm it; use this to send reminders into the future (like "have reached waypoint, refuel me");</li>
          <li><tt>SetComment</tt>: change planet comment;</li>
          <li><tt>WaitOneTurn</tt>: wait one turn, performing whatever orders that were given before;</li>
          <li><tt>Restart</tt>: restart auto task from the beginning.</li>
        </ul></li>
      </ul>

      <h2>Reference</h2>
      <dl>
        <di term="Keys:"> <kbd>Enter</kbd> from <a href="pcc2:planetscreen">planet screen</a>;</di>
        <di term="Related command:"> <a href="int:name:ui.gotoscreen">UI.GotoScreen</a>;</di>
        <di term="Keymap:"> <a href="int:name:autotaskscreen">AutoTaskScreen</a>;</di>
        <di term="Script context:"> <a href="int:name:planet:context">Planet()</a>.</di>
      </dl>
    </page>

    <!-- Base screen -->
    <page id="pcc2:basescreen">
      <h1>Base Screen</h1>

      <p>This screen allows you to control your starbases.
        The following keys are supported in addition to <a href="pcc2:cscreen">Control Screen</a> keys.</p>

      <kl>
        <ki key="T">Upgrade tech levels;</ki>
        <ki key="D"><a href="pcc2:buildings">Build defense</a>;</ki>
        <ki key="B"><a href="pcc2:buildship">Build ship</a>;</ki>
        <ki key="Q"><a href="pcc2:queuemanager">Manage build queue</a>;</ki>
        <ki key="M">Change base mission;</ki>
        <ki key="R">Fix&#47;recycle a ship;</ki>
        <ki key="A">Build torpedoes&#47;fighters.</ki>
      </kl>

      <p>The current ship build order will be shown on the control screen,
        along with the queue position ("Q:") if known.</p>

      <h2>Reference</h2>
      <dl>
        <di term="Keys:"> <kbd>F3</kbd> from almost everywhere;</di>
        <di term="Related command:"> <a href="int:name:ui.gotoscreen">UI.GotoScreen</a>;</di>
        <di term="Keymap:"> <a href="int:name:basescreen">BaseScreen</a>;</di>
        <di term="Script context:"> <a href="int:name:planet:context">Planet()</a>.</di>
      </dl>
    </page>

    <!-- Base Task screen -->
    <page id="pcc2:basetaskscreen">
      <h1>Base Task Screen</h1>

      <p>This screen supports allows defining an Auto Task for a starbase.
        Typically, a starbase auto task tries to submit ship build orders.
        The following keys are supported in addition to <a href="pcc2:taskscreen">Auto Task Screen</a> keys.</p>

      <kl>
        <ki key="E">Edit current <tt>EnqueueShip</tt> or <tt>BuildShip</tt> command using <a href="pcc2:buildship">ship build screen</a>;</ki>
      </kl>

      <h2>Base Task Commands</h2>
      <ul>
        <li>Order Commands:
        <ul>
          <li><tt>EnqueueShip</tt>: choose a ship design on the <a href="pcc2:buildship">Ship Build screen</a>. The ship will be built when resources are available and the base's previous build order (if any) has completed;</li>
          <li><tt>SetMission</tt>, <tt>SetFCode</tt>: self-explanatory;</li>
        </ul></li>
        <li>Cargo Commands: <tt>CargoUnloadAllShips</tt>: unload Tritanium, Molybdenum, Duranium, colonists, supplies, and cash from all ships in orbit of this planet.
          You can edit the command using <kbd>Space</kbd> to fit your needs;</li>
        <li>Miscellaneous Commands:
        <ul>
          <li><tt>Notify</tt>: generate a <a href="pcc2:notify">message</a> and wait until you confirm it; use this to send reminders into the future (like "have reached waypoint, refuel me");</li>
          <li><tt>SetComment</tt>: change ship comment;</li>
          <li><tt>WaitOneTurn</tt>: wait one turn, performing whatever orders that were given before;</li>
          <li><tt>Restart</tt>: restart auto task from the beginning.</li>
        </ul></li>
      </ul>

      <h2>Reference</h2>
      <dl>
        <di term="Keys:"> <kbd>Enter</kbd> from <a href="pcc2:basescreen">base screen</a>;</di>
        <di term="Related command:"> <a href="int:name:ui.gotoscreen">UI.GotoScreen</a>;</di>
        <di term="Keymap:"> <a href="int:name:autotaskscreen">AutoTaskScreen</a>;</di>
        <di term="Script context:"> <a href="int:name:planet:context">Planet()</a>.</di>
      </dl>
    </page>

    <!-- History Screen -->
    <page id="pcc2:historyscreen">
      <h1>Ship History Screen</h1>

      <p>PCC2 records information about own and enemy ships, which can be displayed on this screen.
        The screen shows the last known equipment and ammunition of the ship.
        A list shows the last known positions and masses.</p>

      <p>The following keys are supported in addition to <a href="pcc2:cscreen">Control Screen</a> keys.</p>

      <kl>
        <ki key="C">For enemy ships, displays the last known cargo, and computes a few useful things from the ship's mass. For own ships, opens the <a href="pcc2:cargo">cargo transfer</a>;</ki>
        <ki key="S">Show ship <a href="pcc2:specsheet">specification sheet</a>;</ki>
        <ki key="Tab">cycle through ships that were at this place. With <kbd>Ctrl</kbd>: marked ships only. With <kbd>Shift</kbd>: backward.</ki>
      </kl>

      <h2>Reference</h2>
      <dl>
        <di term="Keys:"> <kbd>F6</kbd> from almost everywhere;</di>
        <di term="Related command:"> <a href="int:name:ui.gotoscreen">UI.GotoScreen</a>;</di>
        <di term="Keymap:"> <a href="int:name:historyscreen">HistoryScreen</a>;</di>
        <di term="Script context:"> <a href="int:name:ship:context">Ship()</a>.</di>
      </dl>
    </page>

    <!-- Fleet Screen -->
    <page id="pcc2:fleetscreen">
      <h1>Fleet Screen</h1>

      <p>Ships can be grouped into fleets.
        A fleet shares a common waypoint and speed.
        Fleets have a leader which defines the course.</p>

      <p>The screen displays a list with all fleet members.
        Some operations pertain to the whole fleet, some to the currently-chosen member.</p>

      <p>The following keys are supported in addition to <a href="pcc2:cscreen">Control Screen</a> keys.</p>
      <kl>
        <ki key="A">Change fleet's waypoint. See <a href="pcc2:navchart">Navigation Chart</a>;</ki>
        <ki key="B">Make the selected ship the leader of the fleet;</ki>
        <ki key="C"><a href="pcc2:cargo">Cargo transfer</a>;</ki>
        <ki key="D"><a href="pcc2:multicargo">Multi-ship cargo transfer</a>;</ki>
        <ki key="F"><a href="pcc2:fcode">Change friendly code</a> of current ship;</ki>
        <ki key="G">Give ship away (PHost feature). Note that the ship cannot be member of the fleet when owned by someone else;</ki>
        <ki key="J">Join another fleet. All ships of this fleet will become members of the other fleet;</ki>
        <ki key="N">Change name of current fleet. The name is optional;</ki>
        <ki key="P">Split fleet. This will make two new fleets, one containing all the marked ships (use <kbd>.</kbd>), one containing the unmarked ones;</ki>
        <ki key="S"><a href="pcc2:specsheet">Show specification sheet</a>;</ki>
        <ki key="T">Tow another fleet member;</ki>
        <ki key="U"><a href="pcc2:cargo">Unload ship to planet</a>;</ki>
        <ki key="W">Change fleet's warp speed. On the warp speed dialog, type a number to set that warp factor;</ki>
        <ki key="Ins">Add ship to battle simulation;</ki>
        <ki key="Ctrl-Ins">Add all ships to battle simulation;</ki>
        <ki key="Del">Remove ship from fleet;</ki>
        <ki key="Ctrl-Del">Remove all ships from the fleet (dissolve it);</ki>
        <ki key="Ctrl-W">Change fleet's waypoint to match the scanner;</ki>
        <ki key="Ctrl-Z">Clear fleet's waypoint.</ki>
      </kl>

      <p>To change the fleet's waypoint, double-click into the map.
        Alternatively, use the <a href="pcc2:navchart">Navigation Chart</a> (<kbd>A</kbd>).</p>

      <h2>Reference</h2>
      <dl>
        <di term="Keys:"> <kbd>F10</kbd> from almost everywhere;</di>
        <di term="Related command:"> <a href="int:name:ui.gotoscreen">UI.GotoScreen</a>;</di>
        <di term="Keymap:"> <a href="int:name:fleetscreen">FleetScreen</a>;</di>
        <di term="Script context:"> <a href="int:name:ship:context">Ship()</a> (for current member).</di>
      </dl>
    </page>

    <!-- Environment Scan -->
    <page id="pcc2:envscreen">
      <h1>Planet Environment Scan</h1>

      <p>This screen display information about the environment (minerals, population, etc.)
        of your own planets, unowned or enemy planets you visit, or you have previously seen.
        Depending on the exact situation, you'll see different information,
        often merged from different scans (e.g. minerals from history and current population).</p>

      <kl>
        <ki key="C">Ground combat simulator.
          For own planets, displays an overview of how many clans an enemy would have to send to conquer the planet.
          For enemy planets, you can enter a number of clans,
          and PCC2 will compute the range of possible outcomes.</ki>
      </kl>

      <h2>Details</h2>

      <p>The text on the left side can be scrolled if it's too long.</p>
      <ul>
        <li>"won't die if less than": you can exceed the maximum population, but the overpopulation will not die up to this limit;</li>
        <li>"pillage/RGA max. turns": when you're continuously attacking the planet, the population will be gone after this many turns;</li>
        <li>"base tax rate": how much money you can collect from the natives at a tax rate that produces no change in happiness (Safe Tax method).
          The number of colonists is show in addition if it differs from the number of megacredits;</li>
        <li>"max tax rate": how much money you can collect from the natives with a happiness change
          of -30. You can normally collect even more, but then negative effects (no growth, riots) will kick in.</li>
      </ul>

      <h2>Reference</h2>
      <dl>
        <di term="Keys:"> <kbd>F5</kbd>/<kbd>Shift-F5</kbd>/<kbd>Ctrl-F5</kbd> from almost everywhere;</di>
        <di term="Related command:"> <a href="int:name:ui.planetinfo">UI.PlanetInfo</a>.</di>
      </dl>
    </page>

    <!-- Starchart -->
    <page id="pcc2:starchart">
      <h1>Starchart</h1>

      <p>The starchart displays your view of the universe.
        Depending on game settings, you may see all planet positions from the start, or you may need to come close to see them.
        You will only see enemy ships, enemy populations on planets, wormholes, and minefields, when you're close enough and are using the Sensor Sweep mission.
        PCC2 will track units so if you saw something a few turns ago, you will still see it.</p>

      <kl>
        <ki key="Arrows">Use the arrows to move around in steps of 10 (or <a href="prefixarg">prefix argument</a>). Hold <kbd>Shift</kbd> to go a single light year, <kbd>Ctrl</kbd> to go 100;</ki>
        <ki key="+, -">Zoom;</ki>
        <ki key="Space">Lock onto planet. With <kbd>Ctrl</kbd>, only marked units;</ki>
        <ki key="Enter">Lock onto ship. With <kbd>Ctrl</kbd>, only marked units;</ki>
        <ki key="F1">Go to ship screen (if locked at a ship);</ki>
        <ki key="F2">Go to planet screen (if locked at a planet);</ki>
        <ki key="F3, F8">Go to base screen (if locked at a planet with base);</ki>
        <ki key="F4, ESC">Exit starchart;</ki>
        <ki key="F5"><a href="pcc2:envscreen">Planet information</a> (if locked at a planet);</ki>
        <ki key="F6"><a href="pcc2:historyscreen">Starship History</a> (if locked at a ship or near a ship's position);</ki>
        <ki key="F7"><a href="pcc2:search">Search object</a>;</ki>
        <ki key="Ctrl-H"><a href="pcc2:search">Search objects</a> at this location;</ki>
        <ki key="F9">Edit current unit's or marker's comment;</ki>
        <ki key="Shift-F9, Ctrl-F9">Edit current planet's comment;</ki>
        <ki key="Alt-F9">Edit current marker's comment;</ki>
        <ki key="PgUp, PgDn">Browse through units of this type in Id order. With <kbd>Ctrl</kbd>, only marked units. With <kbd>Shift</kbd>, also include units we're not playing;</ki>
        <ki key="L"><a href="pcc2:listship">List ships</a> at this point;</ki>
        <ki key="Ctrl-N"><a href="pcc2:listship">List ships</a> that will be here next turn;</ki>
        <ki key="G"><a href="pcc2:gotoxy">Go to coordinate or sector</a>;</ki>
        <ki key="digit M, Ctrl-M">Create canned marker. <kbd>Ctrl-M</kbd> creates a default marker, <kbd>1 M</kbd> through <kbd>9 M</kbd> create markers 1-9;</ki>
        <ki key="M"><a href="pcc2:minescreen">Minefield information</a>;</ki>
        <ki key="U"><a href="pcc2:ufoscreen">Ufo information</a>;</ki>
        <ki key="I"><a href="pcc2:ionscreen">Ion storm information</a>;</ki>
        <ki key="C">Change color of drawing near cursor;</ki>
        <ki key="V">Move marker we're locked on. Finish moving with <kbd>ESC</kbd>;</ki>
        <ki key="P"><a href="pcc2:draw">Draw</a>;</ki>
        <ki key="T"><a href="pcc2:drawtag">Change drawing tag</a>;</ki>
        <ki key="D"><a href="pcc2:distance">Distance mode</a>;</ki>
        <ki key="R">Range mode. Mark all objects within a rectangular area. Finish with <kbd>ESC</kbd>, cancel with <kbd>Backspace</kbd>;</ki>
        <ki key="Ctrl-R">Toggle or <a href="pcc2:starchart:ranges">configure display of visibility ranges</a>;</ki>
        <ki key="X">When looking at a wormhole, goes to its other end.
          When looking at a ship, goes to its waypoint and back.
          On circular wrapped map, switch between this point and its "outside" image;</ki>
        <ki key="Del">Delete drawing near cursor. Confirm with <kbd>Enter</kbd> or <kbd>Y</kbd>, cancel with <kbd>ESC</kbd> or <kbd>N</kbd>.
          Pick different drawing to delete using <kbd>Del</kbd>. Delete this line and all adjacent lines using <kbd>A</kbd>;</ki>
        <ki key="Backspace">Go to previous screen;</ki>
        <ki key="Alt-Backspace">Show list of previous screens;</ki>
        <ki key="Alt-O"><a href="pcc2:starchartopts">Starchart options</a>;</ki>
        <ki key="Alt-F"><a href="pcc2:drawtag">Filter drawings</a>;</ki>
        <ki key="Alt-L">Edit <a href="pcc2:labels">unit label expressions</a>;</ki>
      </kl>

      <h2>Option Toggles</h2>
      <kl>
        <ki key="Alt-M">Toggle display of minefields;</ki>
        <ki key="Alt-A">Toggle display of ships as dots or triangles;</ki>
        <ki key="Alt-D">Toggle display of <a href="pcc2:labels">unit labels</a>;</ki>
        <ki key="Alt-I">Toggle display of ion storms;</ki>
        <ki key="Alt-V">Toggle display of ship vectors;</ki>
        <ki key="Alt-T">Toggle highlight of marked units;</ki>
        <ki key="Alt-S">Toggle display of sector borders;</ki>
        <ki key="Alt-B">Toggle display of map borders;</ki>
        <ki key="Alt-U">Toggle display of Ufos;</ki>
        <ki key="Alt-P">Toggle display of drawings;</ki>
        <ki key="Alt-W">Toggle display of warp well boundaries;</ki>
        <ki key="Alt-N">Toggle display of message flags. A flag is displayed if there is a <a href="pcc2:msgin">message</a> for a unit. Press <kbd>Shift-N</kbd> to read the messages;</ki>
        <ki key="Alt-Y">Toggle whether minefields are shown after decay.</ki>
      </kl>

      <h2>Object View</h2>

      <p>When you select an object (ship or planet) on the starchart, PCC2 will display two map overlays:
        a list containing all objects at this place, and an overlay panel containing information about the current object.
        While the info panel is displayed, most keys of the respective control screen are active.
        For example, while locked at a ship, <kbd>M</kbd> changes the ship's mission instead of opening a minefield info view.
        In addition, the following keys are accepted:</p>

      <kl>
        <ki key="Tab">Cycle through units at this place. With <kbd>Ctrl</kbd>, only marked units. With <kbd>Shift</kbd>, go backwards;</ki>
        <ki key="B">Replace planet view by starbase view; if no starbase present, try to build one;</ki>
        <ki key="P">Replace starbase view by planet view;</ki>
        <ki key="A">On planet view, <a href="pcc2:buildings">build structures</a>;</ki>
        <ki key="ESC">Hide view.</ki>
      </kl>

      <h2>Starchart Symbols</h2>
      <ul>
        <li>Starships are color-coded: <b><font color="green">&#x2022;&#160;green</font></b> for own,
          <b><font color="yellow">&#x2022;&#160;gold</font></b> for allied,
          <b><font color="red">&#x2022;&#160;red</font></b> for enemy units.
          Ships are dots or tiny triangles (<kbd>Alt-A</kbd> to toggle) when in free space,
          circles when in orbit of a planet.
          When ships of different kind orbit a planet, the ring is
          <b><font color="yellow">&#x2022;&#160;yellow</font></b>;</li>
        <li>Planets have a <b><font color="blue">&#x2022;&#160;blue</font></b> ring when they're yours,
          a <font>gray</font> one when they are owned by an enemy,
          a <font>bronze</font> one when they are owned by an ally,
          a <font>gray dotted</font> one when they are unowned,
          and no ring at all when nothing is known;</li>
        <li>Planets that have bases have an additional "+"-style cross;</li>
        <li>Own minefields are <font>green</font>,
          allied minefields are <font>bronze</font>,
          enemy fields are <font>gray</font>.
          Web fields are denser than normal ones;</li>
        <li>Explosions are a mix of yellow and red pixels;</li>
        <li>Sector borders (gray dotted lines) are drawn every 100 lightyears
          (also see <a href="pcc2:gotoxy">Go to X/Y or sector</a>);</li>
        <li>The map boundary is drawn as a dashed line.
          On a wrapped (circular/rectangular) map, crossing the map border will have your ship re-enter the map at the other side.
          On a non-wrapped map, the map boundary has no in-game meaning.</li>
      </ul>

      <p>Whether a player is ally or enemy is determined by the <a href="pcc2:teams">Teams</a> setting.</p>

      <h2>Reference</h2>
      <dl>
        <di term="Keys:"> <kbd>F4</kbd> from almost everywhere;</di>
        <di term="Related command:"> <a href="int:name:ui.gotochart">UI.GotoChart</a>,
          <a href="int:name:chart.setview">Chart.SetView</a>;</di>
        <di term="Keymap:">
          <a href="int:name:starchart">Starchart</a> (normal),
          <a href="int:name:shiplock">ShipLock</a>,
          <a href="int:name:planetlock">PlanetLock</a>,
          <a href="int:name:baselock">BaseLock</a>),
          <a href="int:name:unknownplanetlock">UnknownPlanetLock</a> (when locked at appropriate object);</di>
        <di term="Script context:"> corresponding to locked object.</di>
      </dl>
    </page>

    <!-- Starchart Options -->
    <page id="pcc2:starchartopts">
      <h1>Starchart Options</h1>

      <p>This dialog configures the <a href="pcc2:starchart">starchart</a> as well as all other starchart views displayed throughout the program.
        It consists of multiple pages.</p>

      <p>On every page, there is a small menu with an <kbd>S</kbd> button.
        Use this to choose where the settings from this page are stored:</p>

      <ul>
        <li><b>User configuration file</b>: your general <tt><a href="config:pcc2ini">pcc2.ini</a></tt> file
          in your <a href="config:intro">profile directory</a>, valid for all games;</li>
        <li><b>Game configuration file</b>: <tt>pcc2.ini</tt> file in the game directory,
          valid for this game only.</li>
      </ul>

      <h2>Display page</h2>

      <p>Configures what objects you want to see.
        For circular objects (ion storms, minefields, ufos), you can also configure whether you want them filled (green "F") or outlined (blue "X").
        For the sector borders, there is an additional possibility "I" to restrict sector borders to the "inside" of a circular wrapped map.
        Drawing the sector borders outside the map is very expensive so it's possible to turn it off.</p>

      <p>Regular starcharts, small-size starcharts and scanners can be configured differently.
        Click the checkbox to the right of the object name to set the value for all three configurations at once.
        Click the "+" to the left of the name to show separate options for the three configurations.</p>

      <h2>Geometry page</h2>

      <p>Configures your map shape and behaviour.</p>

      <dl>
        <di term="Normal (plane)">a normal map, with "infinite" unchartered space outside the star cluster.
          You can modify the <em>Center</em> and <em>Size</em> fields to adjust the position of the sector grid if your map has a nonstandard shape.
          The Center is the location of the center of the map (a coordinate pair, two values),
          the Size is the size (diameter), and can be one or two values;</di>

        <di term="Wrapped (rectangular, Sphere)">rectangular wrap.
          A ship exiting the map to the right enters it again on the left.
          This is a very popular setting these days; there are a handful add-ons implementing it and it is built into PHost.
          <em>Center</em> and <em>Size</em> define the size of the map, as for <em>Normal</em>.
          When you use PHost with wrap enabled, PCC2 will configure itself automatically;</di>

        <di term="Round wrap (circular, PWrap)">circular wrap.
          The map is not a rectangle, but a circle.
          Ships leaving the circle enter it again on the opposite edge.
          The <em>Size</em> here is a single value specifying the radius of the circle.</di>
      </dl>

      <p><font color="red"><b>Note:</b></font> For <em>Normal</em> and <em>Wrapped</em>, the Size is the side length of the rectangle.
        This differs from PCC 1.x where it was half of that.</p>

      <h2>Markers page</h2>

      <p>You can configure 10 markers you can quickly create from starcharts or scanners
        (default marker: <kbd>Ctrl+M</kbd>, markers 1 to 9: <kbd>1 M</kbd> to <kbd>9 M</kbd>).</p>

      <kl>
        <ki key="Space">Pick shape and color for this marker;</ki>
        <ki key="N">Enter a name for this marker. This name is just a reminder for you and has no other effect.</ki>
      </kl>

      <h2>Mouse page</h2>

      <p>This page configures what objects the cursor "locks on" when you press a mouse button,
        <kbd>Space</kbd> or <kbd>Enter</kbd>, as well as what happens when you use the mouse wheel.</p>

      <h2>Reference</h2>
      <dl>
        <di term="Keys:"> <kbd>Alt-O</kbd> from <a href="pcc2:starchart">starchart</a>;</di>
        <di term="See also:"> <a href="pcc2:settings">Settings dialog</a>.</di>
      </dl>
    </page>

    <!-- Ranges -->
    <page id="pcc2:starchart:ranges">
      <h1>Visibility Ranges</h1>

      <p>PCC can display visibility ranges in the starcharts.
        Objects that are visible are displayed normally; everything outside the range receives a blue shade.</p>

      <kl>
        <ki key="R">Choose origin of scan.
          "Own units/ships/planets" will display ranges around your units.
          "Marked units" will display ranges around <a href="pcc2:selectionmgr">marked</a> ships and planets;</ki>
        <ki key="T">When enabled, draws ranges around your <a href="pcc2:teams">team member's</a> units as well.
          This option is ignored for the "Marked" origin.</ki>
        <ki key="Down">Choose from predefined ranges according to host configuration:
        <ul>
          <li>Sensor range: range of sensor sweep mission (<cfg>SensorRange</cfg>);</li>
          <li>Visibility range: distance at which ships in free space are visible (<cfg>ScanRange</cfg>);</li>
          <li>Minefields visible: distance at which minefield are visible to Mine Sweep (<cfg>MineScanRange</cfg>);</li>
          <li>Dark sense: range of the Dark Sense mission (<cfg>DarkSenseRange</cfg>).</li>
        </ul></ki>
      </kl>

      <h2>Reference</h2>
      <dl>
        <di term="Keys:"> <kbd>Ctrl-R</kbd> from <a href="pcc2:starchart">starchart</a>.</di>
      </dl>
    </page>

    <!-- Unit Labels -->
    <page id="pcc2:labels">
      <h1>Unit Labels</h1>

      <p>PCC2 can label planets and ships in the starcharts.
        Labels are defined by <a href="int:expr">expressions</a> which are evaluated for each ship/planet.
        Using the <a href="pcc2:starchartopts">starchart options</a> or, in the starchart, the <kbd>Alt-D</kbd> shortcut,
        you can configure in which starchart views the labels are displayed.</p>
      <kl>
        <ki key="Tab">Switch between fields;</ki>
        <ki key="Down">Select from predefined or last-used expressions.</ki>
      </kl>

      <h2>Reference</h2>
      <dl>
        <di term="Keys:"> <kbd>Alt-L</kbd> from <a href="pcc2:starchart">starchart</a>;</di>
        <di term="See also:"> <a href="pcc2:settings">Settings dialog</a>.</di>
      </dl>
    </page>

    <!-- Go to X/Y -->
    <page id="pcc2:gotoxy">
      <h1>Go to X/Y</h1>

      <p>Use this dialog to go to a specific location in the map.</p>

      <p>Enter a coordinate pair in the form "<tt>1111,2222</tt>".</p>

      <p>Alternatively, you can enter a sector number such as "<tt>123</tt>", to be brought to the center of that sector.
        A sector is a 100&#xd7;100 area of space.
        The sector number is displayed in the lower-left corner of the starchart.
        Sector numbers appear on various paper starcharts and are a quick way to refer to an area.
        Unfortunately, they are generally not known to users of programs other than PCC/PCC2.</p>

      <p>In case of a wrapped map, requesting a location outside the existing map area
        brings you to an alias of that location
        (i.e. 900,700 is outside the map, so you'll be brought to 2900,2700).</p>

      <p>When PCC2 shows a coordinate pair (e.g. in a <a href="pcc2:msgin">message</a>),
        that typically serves as a clickable hyperlink that brings you to the starchart.</p>

      <h2>Reference</h2>
      <dl>
        <di term="Keys:"> <kbd>G</kbd> from <a href="pcc2:starchart">starchart</a></di>
      </dl>
    </page>

    <!-- Minefield screen -->
    <page id="pcc2:minescreen">
      <h1>Minefield Information</h1>

      <p>This window shows information about a minefield.
        When not invoked directly from a minefield, displays the nearest one.</p>

      <kl>
        <ki key="Up, Down">Browse through minefields;</ki>
        <ki key="Tab">Browse through minefields with same center;</ki>
        <ki key="S">Show how many beams are needed to sweep this field;</ki>
        <ki key="P">Go to planet controlling this minefield;</ki>
        <ki key="Del">Remove minefield from starchart.
          This will just remove the minefield from the map,
          it will not sweep the field. The field will re-appear when it is scanned again;</ki>
        <ki key="Enter">Show minefield in <a href="pcc2:starchart">starchart</a>.</ki>
      </kl>

      <h2>Reference</h2>
      <dl>
        <di term="Keys:"> <kbd>M</kbd> from <a href="pcc2:starchart">starchart</a>.</di>
      </dl>
    </page>

    <!-- Ufo screen -->
    <page id="pcc2:ufoscreen">
      <h1>Ufo Information</h1>

      <p>This window shows information about an Ufo.
        When not invoked directly from an Ufo, displays the nearest one.</p>

      <p>Ufos are objects created by add-on programs that operate according to add-on rules.
        You cannot directly interact with Ufos through this screen.
        However, you can configure an Ufo to be kept in PCC2's starchart database.
        PCC2 also has some builtin knowledge about PHost's wormholes which are shown as Ufos.</p>

      <kl>
        <ki key="Up, Down">Browse through Ufos;</ki>
        <ki key="Tab">Browse through Ufos with same center;</ki>
        <ki key="X">For wormholes, go to the other end if known;</ki>
        <ki key="K">Toggle whether this Ufo shall be kept in the database;</ki>
        <ki key="Enter">Show Ufo in <a href="pcc2:starchart">starchart</a>.</ki>
      </kl>

      <h2>Reference</h2>
      <dl>
        <di term="Keys:"> <kbd>U</kbd> from <a href="pcc2:starchart">starchart</a>.</di>
      </dl>
    </page>

    <!-- Ion screen -->
    <page id="pcc2:ionscreen">
      <h1>Ion Storm Information</h1>

      <p>This window shows information about an ion storm.
        When not invoked directly from an ion storm, displays the nearest one.</p>
      <kl>
        <ki key="Up, Down">Browse through storms;</ki>
        <ki key="F"><a href="pcc2:ionforecast">Ion storm forecast</a>;</ki>
        <ki key="Enter">Show storm in <a href="pcc2:starchart">starchart</a>.</ki>
      </kl>
      <h2>Reference</h2>
      <dl>
        <di term="Keys:"> <kbd>I</kbd> from <a href="pcc2:starchart">starchart</a>.</di>
      </dl>
    </page>

    <!-- Ion forecast -->
    <page id="pcc2:ionforecast">
      <h1>Ion Storm Forecast</h1>

      <p>This window displays a forecast about the future movement of an ion storm.
        You can move around the scanner beam using the usual keys;
        <kbd>+</kbd> and <kbd>-</kbd> will change the zoom factor,
      <kbd>Tab</kbd> recenters the map.</p>

      <p><kbd>ESC</kbd> closes the window.</p>

      <p>The forecast considers the following properties of ion storms, consistent with Host 3.22.003 and PHost 4:</p>
      <ul>
        <li>Storms don't change their direction by more than 10&#176; per turn;</li>
        <li>Storms smaller than 200 ly move at Warp 6, larger ones move at Warp 2 to 4;</li>
        <li>Storms with more than 250 MeV move at warp 8, regardless of what the above rule says.</li>
      </ul>
      <p>The forecast does not consider growth of the storm, pancaking, and ion storm joining.</p>

      <h2>Reference</h2>
      <dl>
        <di term="Keys:"> <kbd>F</kbd> from <a href="pcc2:ionscreen">ion storm information</a>.</di>
      </dl>
    </page>

    <!-- Console -->
    <page id="pcc2:console">
      <h1>Console</h1>
      <p>The console has two purposes.
        It logs various system messages, such as PCC2's startup phase.
        It also acts as the interface to the script interpreter.
        You can enter expressions and one-line commands.
        When you enter an expression, both the expression and its result will be logged on the console.
        You can therefore use this as a calculator ("what is <tt>17*4</tt>?"),
        and to check PCC2 expressions (<tt>Distance(Ship(10), Ufo(20))</tt>, <tt>Ship(17).Name</tt>)
        or commands (<tt>SetMission 4</tt>).
        For details, refer to <a href="int:intro">PCC2 Interpreter Documentation</a>.</p>

      <p>You can use the following keys:</p>
      <kl>
        <ki key="Enter">Evaluate expression;</ki>
        <ki key="&#x2191;, &#x2193;">Recall previous input and output into input line;</ki>
        <ki key="Ins">Insert last result into input line;</ki>
        <ki key="Tab">Attempt to complete current word (as property name of current object);</ki>
        <ki key="Alt-V">List user-defined properties of the current object, and their values;</ki>
        <ki key="Shift-&#x2191;, Shift-&#x2193;">Scroll through previous output;</ki>
        <ki key="Shift-PgUp, Shift-PgDn">Scroll through previous output.</ki>
      </kl>

      <!-- FIXME: <p><b>When PCC2 is executing a long-running script, it will not otherwise react on keypresses.
           In this case, press <kbd>Ctrl-Pause</kbd> or, if your computer doesn't accept that,
           <kbd>Ctrl-C</kbd>, to abort that script (PCC2 will ask for confirmation).</b></p> -->

      <h2>Reference</h2>
      <dl>
        <di term="Keys:"> <kbd>Alt-C</kbd> from almost everywhere;</di>
        <di term="Related command:"> <a href="int:name:ui.popupconsole">UI.PopupConsole</a>;</di>
        <di term="Script context:"> same as invoking screen.</di>
      </dl>
    </page>

    <!-- Keymap debugger -->
    <page id="pcc2:keymap">
      <h1>Keymap Debugger</h1>

      <p>The keymap debugger can be used to figure out what a key does.
        It is useful if you want to develop scripts.
        On the left, it displays the names of the currently active keymaps, which define what keys are active at this place
        When you press a key, the action it triggers will be displayed on the right.</p>
        <p>To close the keymap debugger, press <kbd>Shift-ESC</kbd>
        (a lone <kbd>ESC</kbd> will also work if it isn't bound by the active keymap).</p>

      <h2>Reference</h2>
      <dl>
        <di term="Keys:"> <kbd>Alt-K</kbd> from almost everywhere;</di>
        <di term="See also:"> <a href="int:index:type:keymap">Keymaps</a> in script manual.</di>
      </dl>
    </page>

    <!-- Selection Manager -->
    <page id="pcc2:selectionmgr">
      <h1>Selection Manager</h1>

      <p>You can mark and objects using <kbd>.</kbd> to keep track of objects you still need to work with.
        This is called the selection.
        In a typical workflow, you all units at the beginning of the turn, and unmark them when you're done with them.</p>

      <p>PCC2 manages eight layers of selections, called "A" to "H".
        At almost any place, you can switch selection layers using <kbd>Alt-&#x2190;</kbd> and <kbd>Alt-&#x2192;</kbd>,
        and you can invoke the Selection Manager using <kbd>Alt-.</kbd>.
        You can use this, for example, to keep track of the planets you're working with on one layer,
        and visualize <a href="pcc2:search">search results</a> on the others.</p>

      <p>The following functions are available on the Selection Manager:</p>
      <kl>
        <ki key="D">Clear one layer (unselect all objects). With <kbd>Ctrl</kbd>: clear all layers;</ki>
        <ki key="I">Invert one layer. With <kbd>Ctrl</kbd>: invert all layers;</ki>
        <ki key="C">Copy/compute the current layer from an expression, see below;</ki>
        <ki key="S">Save current selection layer. With <kbd>Ctrl</kbd>: save all layers;</ki>
        <ki key="L">Load one or all selection layers from a saved file;</ki>
        <ki key="M">Merge one or all selection. Like <kbd>L</kbd>, but adds to the previous selection instead of replacing it;</ki>
        <ki key="F7">List objects on current layer. Activates the layer and shows it in the <a href="pcc2:search">Search dialog</a>.</ki>
        <ki key="Enter">Select new current layer and close Selection Manager;</ki>
        <ki key="ESC">Close selection manager.</ki>
      </kl>

      <h2 id="pcc2:selectionexpr">Selection Expressions</h2>

      <p>You can compute a selection layer's content from other layers' content.
        For example, you can merge two layers using an expression such as <tt>A or B</tt>:
        the result will be a selection that contains all objects that were in A or B.
        In the simplest form, the selection expression contains just a layer name, such as <tt>D</tt>,
        which just copies a layer.</p>

      <p>The following contains possible selection expressions in order of increasing precedence.</p>
      <ul>
        <li>Lowest priority:
        <dl>
          <di term="a&nbsp;Or&nbsp;b">   Logical Or: yields all objects that are in a or b;</di>
          <di term="a&nbsp;+&nbsp;b">    Same as <tt>a Or b</tt>;</di>
          <di term="a&nbsp;Xor&nbsp;b">  Logical Exclusive-or: yields all objects that are in a or b, but not in both;</di>
          <di term="a&nbsp;-&nbsp;b">    Logical Subtraction: yields all objects that are in a, but not in b;</di>
        </dl>
        </li>
        <li>Medium priority:
        <dl>
          <di term="a&nbsp;And&nbsp;b">  Logical And: yields all objects that are in a and in b;</di>
          <di term="a&nbsp;*&nbsp;b">    Same as <tt>a And b</tt>;</di>
        </dl>
        </li>
        <li>Highest priority (unary operators):
        <dl>
          <di term="Not&nbsp;a">         Logical Negation: yields all objects that are not in a;</di>
          <di term="-a">                 Same as <tt>Not a</tt>;</di>
          <di term="(a)">                Parentheses: yields a;</di>
          <di term="P(a), PLANETS(a)">   Yields all the planets contained in a;</di>
          <di term="S(a), SHIPS(a)">     Yields all the ships contained in a;</di>
          <di term="CURRENT">            Yields the current selection;</di>
          <di term="A, B, ..., H">       Yields the contents of the specified layer;</di>
          <di term="P, PLANETS">         Yields the list of all planets;</di>
          <di term="S, SHIPS">           Yields the list of all ships;</di>
          <di term="0">                  Yields an empty selection;</di>
          <di term="1">                  Yields the full selection containing all objects.</di>
        </dl>
        </li>
      </ul>

      <h2>Reference</h2>
      <dl>
        <di term="Keys:"> <kbd>Alt-.</kbd> from almost everywhere;</di>
        <di term="Related command:"> <a href="int:name:ui.selectionmanager">UI.SelectionManager</a>,
        <a href="int:name:selectionexec">SelectionExec</a>.</di>
      </dl>
    </page>

    <!-- Search -->
    <page id="pcc2:search">
      <h1>Search</h1>

      <p>The Search function can locate objects according to a variety of queries.</p>

      <p>Enter your query into the input field.
        Use the controls above to choose search options:</p>
      <kl>
        <ki key="Alt-O">
          Select <em>objects</em> to search. Choose any combination of
          <ul>
            <li>Starships;</li>
            <li>Planets;</li>
            <li>Starbases (starbases are normally searched when Planets is checked, so use this option alone when you want to search starbases only);</li>
            <li>Ufos (includes wormholes);</li>
            <li>Others (ion storms and minefields);</li>
          </ul>
        </ki>
        <ki key="Alt-T">
          Select <em>type</em> of search:
          <ul>
            <li>Name&#47;Id&#47;Comment: searches for a substring of the object's name, or its Id.
            Id numbers can be specified with an optional leading hash sign, as in <tt>#357</tt>.
            Search is case-insensitive;</li>
            <li>Expression true: you enter a script expression
            (see <a href="int:intro">PCC2 Interpreter Documentation</a>).
            The result contains all objects where the expression yields true (nonzero, nonempty);</li>
            <li>Expression false: like Expression true, but returns all objects where the expression yields false (zero, empty);</li>
            <li>Location: enter a coordinate pair (e.g. <tt>1526,2039</tt>).
            The search returns all object located at or covering that point;</li>
          </ul>
        </ki>
        <ki key="Alt-P">Toggle whether you want to find your own played units only.</ki>
      </kl>

      <p>After confirming your input using <kbd>Enter</kbd> or the "Search!" button,
        the result will be displayed in the list box below.
        You can select an object and press <kbd>Enter</kbd> to show its <a href="pcc2:cscreen">control screen</a> or,
        if that is not available, show it in the <a href="pcc2:starchart">starchart</a>.</p>

      <h2>Keys</h2>
      <kl>
        <ki key="Enter">On input line, search. On result list, show result unit's control screen, or show unit on starchart.
          If the dialog has been called from <a href="pcc2:globact">Global Actions</a>, just confirm the result and return;</ki>
        <ki key="Alt-M">("Mark...") Operate on the selection.
        <ul>
          <li>Mark found objects;</li>
          <li>Mark only found objects (this unmarks all other objects);</li>
          <li>Unmark found objects;</li>
        </ul></ki>
        <ki key="Alt-G">("Global...") Open <a href="pcc2:globact">Global Actions</a> operating on the result list;</ki>
        <ki key="Alt-.">Open <a href="pcc2:selectionmgr">selection manager</a>;</ki>
        <ki key="Alt-&#x2190;, Alt-&#x2192;">Next/previous selection layer;</ki>
        <ki key="F1, F6">When a ship is focused in the result list, go to its <a href="pcc2:shipscreen">control screen</a>/<a href="pcc2:historyscreen">history screen</a>;</ki>
        <ki key="F2, F3">When a planet is focused in the result list, go to its <a href="pcc2:planetscreen">control screen</a>/<a href="pcc2:basescreen">starbase screen</a>;</ki>
        <ki key="F4, Shift-Enter">On result list, show object in starchart;</ki>
        <ki key="F7">Put focus onto search query input field.</ki>
      </kl>

      <h2>Reference</h2>
      <dl>
        <di term="Keys:"> <kbd>F7</kbd> from almost everywhere;</di>
        <di term="Related command:"> <a href="int:name:ui.search">UI.Search</a>.</di>
      </dl>
    </page>

    <!-- Incoming messages -->
    <page id="pcc2:msgin">
      <h1>Read Messages</h1>
      <p>This dialog displays your incoming messages.
      You receive messages from other players, your units that report events, or the host.</p>
      <p>Messages are not saved between turns, so there is no need (and no possibility) to delete them after you read them.</p>
      <kl>
        <ki key="&#x2191;, &#x2193;">Browse; with <kbd>Shift</kbd>, don't skip hidden (filtered) messages;</ki>
        <ki key="Ctrl-PgUp, Ctrl-PgDn">Go to first/last message;</ki>
        <ki key="S, F7, /">Search for text;</ki>
        <ki key="N">Continue search;</ki>
        <ki key="F">Forward to another player;</ki>
        <ki key="R">Reply to this message (with quoted text; with <kbd>Ctrl</kbd>, reply-to-all);</ki>
        <ki key="G">Go to object mentioned in this message;</ki>
        <ki key="X">Go to map location mentioned in this message;</ki>
        <ki key="W">Write message to file (with <kbd>Ctrl</kbd>, all);</ki>
        <ki key="A">If message contains a data transmission, accept that;</ki>
        <ki key="Enter">Reply or go to object, whichever PCC2 considers most likely;</ki>
        <ki key="Tab">Subject overview. Messages of similar content are collapsed to one line, for quicker navigation.
          On the overview list, press <kbd>K</kbd> to hide&#47;show a particular group.
          Messages in a hidden group will be skipped by normal browsing;</ki>
        <ki key="digits =">Go to N'th message;</ki>
        <ki key="ESC">Exit.</ki>
      </kl>

      <p>If the message contains a map location (coordinate),
        you can also click it to go there.</p>

      <h2>Filtering Messages</h2>

      <p>You often do not want to read all messages.
        Especially scans (minefields, planets, ion storms) will be processed by PCC
        and drawn into the <a href="pcc2:starchart">starchart</a>, so you do not need to see them.</p>

      <p>PCC includes a client-side message filter.
        Use <kbd>K</kbd> on the subject overview (<kbd>Tab</kbd>) to hide or show a group.
        A group is defined as a set of messages having a common header.</p>

      <p>If you are using PHost, you can also activate a host-side message filter
        on the <a href="pcc2:settings">settings</a> screen.
        I recommend the client-side filter, though, because that allows finer control
        and allows you to change your mind later on.</p>

      <h2>Reference</h2>
      <dl>
        <di term="Keys:"> <kbd>M</kbd> from <a href="pcc2:racescreen">race screen</a>;
          <kbd>Shift-M</kbd> on <a href="pcc2:cscreen">control screen</a> for just a unit's messages,
          <kbd>Alt-U</kbd> from race screen for <tt>util.dat</tt> (machine-readable messages);
          <kbd>Alt-M</kbd> from race screen for messages from a file;</di>
        <di term="See also:"> <a href="pcc2:msgout">Write Messages</a>,
          <a href="pcc2:notify">Notifications</a>.</di>
      </dl>
    </page>

    <!-- Write messages -->
    <page id="pcc2:msgout">
      <h1>Write Messages</h1>
      <p>You can send messages to other players.
        These messages will be sent when the host runs, and receivers can read them next turn.</p>

      <p>Choose races to send message to, or <kbd>U</kbd> to send a universal message (to everyone).
        You'll be placed in the message editor:</p>
      <kl>
        <ki key="Arrows">Move around. With <kbd>Ctrl</kbd>, move whole words;</ki>
        <ki key="Enter">Start new line;</ki>
        <ki key="Home, Ctrl-A">Beginning of line;</ki>
        <ki key="Del, Ctrl-D">Delete character;</ki>
        <ki key="End, Ctrl-E">End of line;</ki>
        <ki key="Ctrl-K">Delete till end of line;</ki>
        <ki key="Ctrl-N">Insert new line before current;</ki>
        <ki key="Ctrl-T">Swap characters before and after cursor;</ki>
        <ki key="Ctrl-Y">Delete line;</ki>
        <ki key="Alt-T">Change receiver of message;</ki>
        <ki key="Alt-W">Toggle word-wrap mode;</ki>
        <ki key="Ins">Toggle insert mode;</ki>
        <ki key="Backspace">Delete character backwards (with <kbd>Ctrl</kbd>: word);</ki>
        <ki key="F10, Ctrl-Enter">Send message.</ki>
      </kl>

      <p>Press <kbd>R</kbd> in the receiver selection window to <a href="pcc2:revise">revise previously-sent messages</a>.</p>

      <h2>Reference</h2>
      <dl>
        <di term="Keys:"> <kbd>W</kbd> from <a href="pcc2:racescreen">race screen</a>.</di>
      </dl>
    </page>

    <!-- Outgoing messages -->
    <page id="pcc2:revise">
      <h1>Revise Messages</h1>

      <p>This dialog shows all messages that you have written but which were not sent yet.
        You can modify or delete them if you changed your mind.</p>

      <p>In addition to most <a href="pcc2:msgin">message reading</a> keys, this accepts the following keys:</p>
      <kl>
        <ki key="Enter, E">Edit message</ki>
        <ki key="T">Change receiver of message</ki>
        <ki key="Del">Delete message</ki>
      </kl>

      <h2>Reference</h2>
      <dl>
        <di term="Keys:"> <kbd>R</kbd> from <a href="pcc2:msgout">message dialog</a>.</di>
      </dl>
    </page>

    <!-- Notification messages -->
    <page id="pcc2:notify">
      <h1>Notification Messages</h1>

      <p>Notification messages are generated by scripts.
        Especially <a href="pcc2:taskscreen">Auto Tasks</a> will generate such messages when there is a problem.</p>

      <p>In addition to most <a href="pcc2:msgin">message reading</a> keys, this accepts the following keys:</p>

      <kl>
        <ki key="C">Confirm message. The auto task or script which generated the message will continue executing when you close this window.
          Note that if the message was caused by an error, it will immediately re-appear unless you have fixed the error.
          If the message was generated by a <tt>Notify</tt> command, it will be gone in your next PCC2 session.</ki>
      </kl>

      <h2>Reference</h2>
      <dl>
        <di term="Keys:"> <kbd>Alt-N</kbd> from <a href="pcc2:racescreen">race screen</a>;</di>
        <di term="See also:"> <a href="int:name:notify">Notify</a> and
          <a href="int:name:addnotify">AddNotify</a> script commands</di>
      </dl>
    </page>

    <!-- Scores -->
    <page id="pcc2:scores">
      <h1>Scores</h1>

      <p>PCC2 records current and past scores in a file <tt>score.cc</tt>.
        Available scores depend on the game being used.
        Typical scores include number of planets, ships, starbases, and the classic score computed from that.
        Additional scores could be number of minefields, PTScore, or number of cactuses.</p>

      <p>PCC2 displays scores in one or more overview tables, and one chart per score.</p>

      <kl>
        <ki key="&#x2190;, &#x2192;">Choose between different views;</ki>
        <ki key="Ctrl-&#x2191;, Ctrl-&#x2193;">(overview) Choose race to highlight;</ki>
        <ki key="Ctrl-&#x2190;, Ctrl-&#x2192;">(charts) Choose race to highlight;</ki>
        <ki key="D">(overview) Choose different display mode:
        <ul>
          <li>Normal scoreboard;</li>
          <li>Differences to previous turn (each turn vs. its predecessor);</li>
          <li>Differences to turn X (each turn vs. turn X);</li>
          <li>Percentages (relative strength compared to highlighted race, which is taken as 100%);</li>
          <li>Ratio of total (relative strength compared to all races together);</li>
          <li>Scores by player vs. Scores by team (like <kbd>Y</kbd> key);</li>
        </ul>
        </ki>
        <ki key="Y">Toggle whether scores are displayed by player or team (=sum of players in a team);</ki>
        <ki key="X">Toggle whether scores are displayed as individual lines (default) or cumulative on the diagram views.
          With cumulative display, the third curve does not contain player 3's score, but the sum of players 1, 2 and 3.
          This makes it easier to see events like the ship limit or progress of planet colonisation.
          This kind of diagram is sometimes known as <em>stacked area chart</em>;</ki>
        <ki key="+, -">(overview) Browse through turns;</ki>
        <ki key="R">(overview) Toggle differences-to-previous-turn mode;</ki>
        <ki key="%">(overview) Toggle percentages mode;</ki>
        <ki key="Ctrl-U">(overview) Unsorted.</ki>
      </kl>

      <p>To sort overview tables, click the heading of the column you want to sort by,
        or press <kbd>Ctrl</kbd> plus the score's hotkey (e.g. <kbd>Ctrl-P</kbd> for planets).
        Hogkeys for individual pages are assigned dynamically depending upon which pages are present.</p>

      <p>Team scores are only available when any <a href="pcc2:teams">teams</a> are configured.</p>

      <h2>Reference</h2>
      <dl>
        <di term="Keys:"> <kbd>S</kbd> from <a href="pcc2:racescreen">race screen</a>.</di>
      </dl>
    </page>

    <!-- Imperial Statistics -->
    <page id="pcc2:imperial">
      <h1>Imperial Statistics</h1>

      <p>This screen displays various statistics about your empire.
        Choose a report using the buttons on the right, or the <kbd>Up</kbd> and <kbd>Down</kbd> arrows.
        Underlined words are clickable links, taking you directly to an object or a ready-made <a href="pcc2:search">search query</a>.
        Use the mouse, or <kbd>Tab</kbd> and <kbd>Enter</kbd>, to follow a link.
        Some reports can be customized using the <kbd>#</kbd> menu.</p>

      <ul>
        <li><b>Totals</b> shows total unit count, minerals, populations and production;</li>
        <li><b>Minerals</b> shows your top Neutronium, Tritanium, Duranium, and Molybdenum planets;</li>
        <li><b>Planets</b> shows planets grouped by native race and climate;</li>
        <li><b>Colony</b> shows your top colonies according to population, supplies, and cash;</li>
        <li><b>Starbases</b> shows your starbases according to various attributes, and ships being built on them;</li>
        <li><b>Starships</b> and <b>Capital</b> show your ships (or just capital ships) according to
          their type and other attributes;</li>
        <li><b>Starchart</b> shows information about your starchart and scanned units;</li>
        <li><b>Weapons</b> gives a statistic about weapons on your ships.</li>
      </ul>

      <h2>Keys</h2>

      <kl>
        <ki key="&#x2191;, &#x2193;">Change page;</ki>
        <ki key="#">Select page-dependant options;</ki>
        <ki key="Ctrl-S">Save current page as HTML file. Using a web browser, you can copy tables from the HTML file into a spreadsheet program;</ki>
        <ki key="ESC">Exit.</ki>
      </kl>

      <h2>Reference</h2>
      <dl>
        <di term="Keys:"> <kbd>I</kbd> from <a href="pcc2:racescreen">race screen</a>.</di>
      </dl>
    </page>

    <!-- Universe Almanac -->
    <page id="pcc2:almanac">
      <h1>Universe Almanac</h1>
      <p>The Universe Almanac displays your game's specification files.
        You can use this to answer questions like "who can build cloakable ships in this game?".</p>

      <p>Scroll around using arrows. Use <kbd>Tab</kbd> to switch between the list, and the toolbar above it.
        Use <kbd>Tab</kbd> or digits to activate different pages.</p>

      <h2>Pages</h2>

      <dl>
        <di term="Races"> All the races in the game, including their abilities;</di>
        <di term="Racial Abilities"> Regular racial abilities known as such ("can assimilate natives"),
          special missions ("pillage"), and other abilities implied by configuration ("2x tax income");</di>
        <di term="Ship Hulls"> All ship hulls;</di>
        <di term="Ship Abilities"> Ship abilities such as Cloak, Hyperdrive, or Alchemy;</di>
        <di term="Engines, Beams, Torpedoes, Fighters"> Other starship components.</di>
      </dl>

      <h2>Filtering</h2>

      <p>To add a filter, click the "Filter" option on the toolbar.
        It will ask for a filter criterion.
        Possible filter criteria depend on the current page, and could be
        name containing a particular word, value being in a particular range (e.g. "50-100 crew")
        or a particular choice ("Tholian hulls", "armed ships").</p>

      <p>To modify a filter, click the "pen" icon, or toggle it using the "toggle" icon.
        To remove it, use the "&#x2717;" icon.</p>

      <p>Some pages have quick filter buttons that show you associated information
        (e.g. all racial abilities for a race).</p>

      <h2>Sorting</h2>

      <p>You can sort the lists.
        To sort, click the "Sort" option on the toolbar.
        Depending on the number of sort orders available, this will toggle or offer a list.</p>

      <h2>Keys</h2>

      <kl>
        <ki key="Space">Add/edit/toggle filter or sort (like mouse click);</ki>
        <ki key="Del">Remove filter;</ki>
        <ki key="Alt-A">Quick filter: abilities;</ki>
        <ki key="Alt-P">Quick filter: players;</ki>
        <ki key="Alt-T">Quick filter: hulls.</ki>
      </kl>

      <h2>Reference</h2>
      <dl>
        <di term="Keys:"> <kbd>Shift-A</kbd> from <a href="pcc2:racescreen">race screen</a>.</di>
      </dl>
    </page>

    <!-- Team editor -->
    <page id="pcc2:teams">
      <h1>Teams</h1>
      <p>You can use teams to model formal and informal alliances.
        Units of races in the same team as you will be shown in yellow instead of red:
        use this to mark your allies.</p>

      <p>Note that teams do not affect gameplay.
        Teams are purely a client-side display feature
        (however, when you put two races into the same team, they will by default behave friendly in the <a href="pcc2:bsim">Battle Simulator</a>).
        If you wish to behave friendly to your team-mates, you need to set up a formal <a href="pcc2:allies">alliance</a>.</p>

      <p>PCC2 supports optional automatic synchronisation of teams.
        Whenever you offer an alliance to someone, they will be put into your team.
        If there is someone in your team whom you do not offer an alliance, they will be dropped from the team.
        This way, you normally have to deal with your alliances only, and can let the teams manage themselves.
        If you do not like this feature, turn it off using <kbd>A</kbd>.</p>

      <kl>
        <ki key="Arrows">Move around;</ki>
        <ki key="Space">Make current race (line) belong to current team (column);</ki>
        <ki key="N">Assign name to current team;</ki>
        <ki key="A">Toggle <em>auto-sync</em> option.</ki>
      </kl>

      <h2>Reference</h2>
      <dl>
        <di term="Keys:"> <kbd>T</kbd> from <a href="pcc2:racescreen">race screen</a>;</di>
        <di term="See also:"> <a href="pcc2:allies">Alliances</a>.</di>
      </dl>
    </page>

    <!-- Alliance editor -->
    <page id="pcc2:allies">
      <h1>Alliances</h1>
      <p>This dialog allows you to configure alliances.
        It is only available if your host version supports alliances.</p>

      <p>The left side lists all other players together with a quick status:</p>
      <ul>
        <li>red: no alliance</li>
        <li>yellow: partial alliance (they have offered but you didn't, or the other way around)</li>
        <li>green: alliance established</li>
        <li>bright red: you have declared them an enemy</li>
      </ul>

      <p>On the right, the selected player's alliance status is broken down.
        The actual selection depends on the host version.
        You can edit alliances here.
        Possible settings include "not offered" (blank checkbox), "offered" (blue <font color="blue">X</font>), and "conditional offer" (green <font color="green">C</font>).
        A conditional offer can only by used by the partner if they offer the same level to you.</p>

      <p>Depending on your host version, the following levels could be available with different settings:</p>
      <ul>
        <li><b>Alliance offer</b> (PHost): You have offered them an alliance (but not necessarily any privileges).</li>
        <li><b>Standard alliance</b> (THost): You have offered them an alliance. You will not attack them.</li>
        <li><b>Ship alliance</b> (PHost): You allow them ship-related privileges.</li>
        <li><b>Planet alliance </b> (PHost): You allow them planet-related privileges.</li>
        <li><b>Minefield alliance </b> (PHost): You allow them free flight through your minefields.</li>
        <li><b>Combat alliance </b> (PHost): You will not attack them.</li>
        <li><b>Vision alliance </b> (PHost, THost): They will see everything you see.</li>
      </ul>

      <p>The following keys are active in this dialog:</p>
      <kl>
        <ki key="Arrows, Tab">Move around</ki>
        <ki key="Space">Toggle current alliance or alliance level</ki>
      </kl>

      <h2>Reference</h2>
      <dl>
        <di term="Keys:"> <kbd>A</kbd> from <a href="pcc2:racescreen">race screen</a>;</di>
        <di term="See also:"> <a href="pcc2:teams">Teams</a>.</di>
      </dl>
    </page>

    <!-- PHost commands -->
    <page id="pcc2:auxcmds">
      <h1>Edit auxiliary commands</h1>

      <p>This menu displays all auxiliary commands (mainly for the PHost command processor).
        This feature is for people who know what they are doing.</p>

      <p>You can add, modify and delete commands.
        That PCC2 automatically extracts commands from messages.
        The commands will not be visible on the normal <a href="pcc2:msgout">outgoing message list</a>.</p>

      <kl>
        <ki key="Arrows">Move around;</ki>
        <ki key="Del">Delete current command;</ki>
        <ki key="Ins">Add a new command;</ki>
        <ki key="Space">Modify the current command (see below).</ki>
      </kl>

      <p>Note that PCC2 knows about the interaction between commands.
        When you add a new command that cancels a previous one, PCC2 will notice and replace the old command with the new one.
        For example, adding <tt>allies drop 3</tt> will replace a previous <tt>allies add 3</tt> command,
        and adding <tt>give ship 3 to 5</tt> will replace a previous <tt>give ship 3 to 9</tt>.
        The <kbd>Space</kbd> bar therefore simply gives you an input line containing the current command,
        allowing you to edit it into a new one that possibly replaces the old one.
        You can, however, also enter a completely new command which will be added to the list.
        Likewise, <kbd>Ins</kbd> gives you a blank input line for a new command which will be added anew or replaces an old command.</p>

      <p>PCC2 will also insert commands at sensible places (for example,
        <tt>allies add</tt> always precedes <tt>allies config</tt>), you cannot reorder them.</p>

      <h2>Reference</h2>
      <dl>
        <di term="Keys:"> <kbd>Alt-E</kbd> from <a href="pcc2:racescreen">race screen</a>.</di>
      </dl>
    </page>

    <!-- Reset -->
    <page id="pcc2:reset">
      <h1>Reset Location</h1>

      <p>This function allows you to reset all units at a particular location to the status they had at the beginning of the turn.
        Most things can simply be reverted manually (e.g. just re-enter the mission the ship had at the beginning of the turn),
        but sometimes this is quite tedious.
        This function can also be used when the turn file has been messed up due to a bug in a program.</p>

      <p>Because units can interact, you must reset all units at a location in a group.
        It is not possible to reset a single ship, maybe: if that ship has transferred cargo somewhere,
        the receiver of that cargo must be reset as well.</p>

      <p>PCC2 divides properties into two groups; you can reset them independant of each other:</p>

      <kl>
        <ki key="C">Cargo, structures, builds. Resets everything that has to do with cargo, i.e. build orders,
          planetary structures (which are built from money and supplies), built starship components or weapons,
          and ship build orders;</ki>
        <ki key="M">Missions, orders, names. Resets missions, friendly codes, names, tax rates, waypoints, etc.
          These do not interact with other units.</ki>
      </kl>

      <p>Other keys:</p>
      <kl>
        <ki key="L">List affected units;</ki>
        <ki key="Enter">Confirm;</ki>
        <ki key="ESC">Cancel.</ki>
      </kl>

      <p>Note that this function does not reset <em>everything</em> to its original place.
        In particular, client-side information such as the unit's comment are not recovered.
        In addition, planets.nu does not store original values for values such as friendly codes,
        so this function will recover the value at the beginning of the session, but not at the beginning of the turn for those.</p>

      <h2>Reference</h2>
      <dl>
        <di term="Keys:"> <kbd>Alt-R</kbd> on <a href="pcc2:cscreen">control screens</a>.</di>
      </dl>
    </page>

    <!-- Battle simulator -->
    <page id="pcc2:bsim">
      <h1>Battle Simulator</h1>

      <p>The Battle Simulator allows you to simulate fights between any number of ships and planets,
        to determine your chances against possible enemy fleets.
        You can use ships from the game, or build your own.</p>

      <kl>
        <ki key="Ins">Add new ship (asks for hull type, assigns default owner);</ki>
        <ki key="Ctrl-Ins, *">Insert multiple copies of the current ship;</ki>
        <ki key="P">Add planet. You can have one planet per simulation. Set the planet's beam technology using <kbd>B</kbd> to add a starbase. A planet will always appear at the end of the list;</ki>
        <ki key="Enter">Run the simulation once and <a href="pcc2:simresult">show results</a>;</ki>
        <ki key="Del">Remove this unit;</ki>
        <ki key="Ctrl-Del">Clear simulation setup;</ki>
        <ki key="F1">(ship) Show this ship on <a href="pcc2:shipscreen">ship screen</a> if possible;</ki>
        <ki key="F2">(planet) Show this planet on <a href="pcc2:planetscreen">planet screen</a> if possible;</ki>
        <ki key="F4">Show this unit on <a href="pcc2:starchart">starchart</a> if possible;</ki>
        <ki key="Ctrl-Up, Ctrl-Down">(ship) Move ship up&#47;down (has no effect on simulation);</ki>
        <ki key="1">(ship) Edit primary weapon (beams);</ki>
        <ki key="2">(ship) Edit secondary weapon (torpedoes, fighters);</ki>
        <ki key="A">(ship) Edit aggressiveness (PE, Kill), (planet) Edit number of starbase torpedoes. You can enter a count for each type, start typing or use <kbd>&#x2190;</kbd>/<kbd>&#x2192;</kbd>;</ki>
        <ki key="B">(planet) Edit beam tech level. Nonzero beam tech means a starbase is present;</ki>
        <ki key="C">(ship) Edit crew;</ki>
        <ki key="D">(ship) Edit damage, (planet) Edit number of defense posts;</ki>
        <ki key="E">(ship) Edit engine (for engine&#47;shield bonus computation);</ki>
        <ki key="F">Edit <a href="pcc2:fcode">friendly code</a>;</ki>
        <ki key="Shift-F">Move to next unit, and give it a numeric fcode above the previous unit's code;</ki>
        <ki key="G">(planet) Edit number of starbase fighters;</ki>
        <ki key="I">Edit Id number;</ki>
        <ki key="K">(ship) Edit ship ratings for FLAK simulation;</ki>
        <ki key="L">Edit experience level (if active on your host);</ki>
        <ki key="M">(ship) Edit mass (custom ships only);</ki>
        <ki key="N">Edit name (for planets, choose from known planet names);</ki>
        <ki key="O">Edit owner;</ki>
        <ki key="P">(planet) Edit population (and compute number of defense posts from that);</ki>
        <ki key="R">Toggle random friendly codes. When enabled, the friendly code will be set to a random numeric value before the simulation. You can choose to randomize some digits only by assigning a friendly code containing "#";</ki>
        <ki key="S">(ship) Edit shield level, (planet) Edit number of starbase defense posts;</ki>
        <ki key="T">(ship) Edit hull type, (planet) Edit starbase torpedo tech level;</ki>
        <ki key="V">(ship) Toggle cloak status;</ki>
        <ki key="X">Edit intercept target (for Intercept Attack battle order);</ki>
        <ki key="Y">Edit <a href="pcc2:simfunctions">abilities (hullfuncs)</a>;</ki>
        <ki key=".">Temporarily disable unit (remove from simulation without deleting it) or enable it again;</ki>
        <ki key="# or \">(or right mouse button) Sort ship list;</ki>
        <ki key="U">Update this unit's simulation data with information from game;</ki>
        <ki key="Ctrl-U">Update all unit's simulation data with information from game;</ki>
        <ki key="W">Write this unit's simulation data to game;</ki>
        <ki key="Ctrl-W">Write all unit's simulation data to game;</ki>
        <ki key="Ctrl-A"><a href="pcc2:simallies">Edit alliance relations</a>;</ki>
        <ki key="Ctrl-C"><a href="pcc2:fleetcost">Fleet cost comparison</a>;</ki>
        <ki key="Ctrl-O">Edit <a href="pcc2:simopts">options</a>;</ki>
        <ki key="Ctrl-R">Read saved simulation from a file (.ccb);</ki>
        <ki key="Ctrl-S">Save simulation setup to file.</ki>
      </kl>

      <h2>Reference</h2>
      <dl>
        <di term="Keys:"> <kbd>B</kbd> from <a href="pcc2:racescreen">race screen</a></di>
      </dl>
    </page>

    <!-- pcc2:simplanet does no longer exist, there is no planet dialog box anymore. -->

    <!-- Simulator Options -->
    <page id="pcc2:simopts">
      <h1>Battle Simulator Options</h1>
      <kl>
        <ki key="M">Choose mode (host&#47;VCR version). Other options are updated accordingly;</ki>
        <ki key="E">Edit engine&#47;shield bonus (should correspond to Host setting);</ki>
        <ki key="C">Toggle Fed Crew Bonus (should correspond to Host setting);</ki>
        <ki key="R">Toggle random left&#47;right side assignment. PHost does this, THost doesn't;</ki>
        <ki key="L">Choose balancing mode for THost left&#47;right imbalance. Default implemented in THost is "360 kt", PHost doesn't need this and has "none";</ki>
        <ki key="A">Choose whether to honor alliances. When this setting is enabled (default), ships <a href="pcc2:simallies">declared as allies</a> are not attacked;</ki>
        <ki key="B">Set to "one" to limit simulations to one fight per battle. Default is to simulate all;</ki>
        <ki key="S">Toggle seed control. If enabled, a "series" (see <a href="pcc2:simresult">Simulator Result</a>) is guaranteed to simulate all possible results; if disabled, random battles are simulated. Only supported for one-fight THost battles;</ki>
        <ki key="F">Choose whether random friendly codes are applied when you start the simulation with <kbd>Enter</kbd>, or for each simulated battle.</ki>
      </kl>

      <h2>Simulator Modes</h2>
      <ul>
        <li><b>Host</b> simulates classic Host combat;</li>
        <li><b>PHost 2..4</b> simulates PHost combat. PHost uses different order-of-battle than Host (in particular, planets have a battle order), and different formulas;</li>
        <li><b>FLAK</b> is a multi-ship combat engine. Unlike the others that break down multi-ship fights into a series of 1:1 fights, this one fights all ships at once;</li>
        <li><b>NuHost</b> is the variant of Host running on planets.nu and uses slightly different formulas.</li>
      </ul>

      <h2>Balancing</h2>
      <p>The original combat algorithm implemented in Host has the problem of not being exactly symmetric,
        such that it makes a difference whether you end up on the left or right side.
        Various ways to solve this have been suggested.</p>
      <ul>
        <li>With Left/Right Balance: 360 kt, a ship fighting against a carrier from the right-hand side will receive 360&nbsp;kt more mass.
          This is implemented in Host;</li>
        <li>With Left/Right Balance: Master at Arms, a ship fighting a carrier from the right-hand side will receive some bonus fighters and bays.
          This is not implemented in any host version, but the PCC battle simulator has been used to validate the concept;</li>
        <li>With Random Left/Right enabled, sides will be assigned randomly, so you cannot predict where you will end up.
          This is implemented in PHost.</li>
      </ul>

      <h2>Seed Control</h2>
      <p>In Host, there are only 119 possible outcomes of each fight.
        With Seed Control enabled, the Battle Simulator will just compute all of them (instead of randomly choosing).
        Thus, if you're computing a full series, you're guaranteed to have seen all possible outcomes.</p>
      <p>This feature is not supported for PHost or FLAK which have much higher number of outcomes.</p>

      <h2>Reference</h2>
      <dl>
        <di term="Keys:"> <kbd>Ctrl-O</kbd> from <a href="pcc2:bsim">battle simulator</a>.</di>
      </dl>
    </page>

    <!-- Simulator Abilities -->
    <page id="pcc2:simfunctions">
      <h1>Battle Simulator Ship/Planet Abilities</h1>

      <p>You can define special abilities for each ship or planet.
        By default, these abilities are taken from the ship list and configuration.
        You can force a ship to have or not have an ability, independant of what ship list and configuration say.</p>

      <p>Note that not all abilities are supported for all simulator modes.
        All abilities are supported for ships; a subset is supported for planets.</p>

      <ul>
        <li><b>Planet Immunity:</b> the ship is not attacked by aggressive planets.
          Supported for all modes (but works a little different in FLAK mode).</li>
        <li><b>Full Weaponry:</b> the ship does not lose weapons when damaged.
          Supported for all modes.</li>
        <li><b>Commander:</b> the ship boosts other ships' experience level.
          Supported for PHost4 and FLAK simulations (the others have no experience).</li>
        <li><b>3&#215; Beam Kill:</b> beams do triple damage against crew.
          This is a default racial ability of the Privateers.
          Supported for all modes but FLAK.</li>
        <li><b>2&#215; Beam/Torp Charge:</b> beams or torpedoes recharge twice as fast.
          Supported for all modes but FLAK.</li>
        <li><b>Elusive:</b> Torpedoes have only a 10% chance to hit this ship instead of the default 65%.
          Supported for Host and NuHost simulation.</li>
        <li><b>Squadron:</b> The ship actually is a fighter squadron, where each beam represents a fighter.
          Its crew cannot be killed, and if it is destroyed, one fighter dies (one beam is lost) and the ship continues the fight.
          Supported for all modes but FLAK.</li>
        <li><b>Shield Generator:</b> The ship provides additional shields to other ships of the same owner.
          As long as a Shield Generator is present, ships get +25% shield and 50% Engine/Shield bonus,
          for up to two Shield Generators per fight.
          Supported for all modes but FLAK.</li>
        <li><b>Cloaked Fighter Bays:</b> When cloaked, the ship can provide its fighter bays and fighters in other carriers' fights.
          Supported for all modes but FLAK.
          Note that when this ability is used, the "Minimum Fighters Aboard" statistic is no longer useful.</li>
      </ul>

      <h2>Reference</h2>
      <dl>
        <di term="Keys:"> <kbd>Y</kbd> from <a href="pcc2:bsim">battle simulator</a>.</di>
      </dl>
    </page>


    <!-- Simulator Alliance Settings -->
    <page id="pcc2:simallies">
      <h1>Battle Simulator Alliances</h1>

      <p>The simulator can honor alliance and enemy settings.</p>
      <ul>
        <li>If player A offers an alliance to player B, A's ships will not attack B's, even if they are aggressive;</li>
        <li>If player A declares B to be an enemy, A's ships will attack B's when they have a Primary Enemy, even if the Primary Enemy is not B.</li>
      </ul>
      <p>The dialog displays the alliance/enemy matrix, where each line represents an offering/declaring player A,
        and each column represents a receiving player B.
        Move around with the arrows, and use <kbd>Space</kbd> to toggle.
        With the mouse, double-click a field to toggle.</p>

      <kl>
        <ki key="Space">Toggle;</ki>
        <ki key="Ctrl-Tab, F6">Switch page;</ki>
        <ki key="A">Activate Alliance page;</ki>
        <ki key="E">Activate Enemy page;</ki>
        <ki key="S">Toggle symmetric relations. When enabled, declaring an offer/enemy from A to B automatically produces a reverse offer from B to A;</ki>
        <ki key="U">Toggle use of default (game) alliances; see below;</ki>
        <ki key="Enter">Confirm;</ki>
        <ki key="ESC">Cancel.</ki>
      </kl>

      <p>When the option "Use default/game relations" is enabled (default), PCC2 automatically sets these options:</p>
      <ul>
        <li>Players belonging to the same <a href="pcc2:teams">team</a> are treated as allies and do not attack each other;</li>
        <li>Your <a href="pcc2:allies">alliance and enemy settings</a> are used to determine whom you treat friendly or hostile.</li>
      </ul>

      <p>Alliance settings are only honored when the respective option is enabled in the <a href="pcc2:simopts">Simulator Options</a>.
        Enemy settings are always honored.</p>

      <h2>Reference</h2>
      <dl>
        <di term="Keys:"> <kbd>Ctrl-A</kbd> from <a href="pcc2:bsim">Battle Simulator</a>;</di>
        <di term="See also:"> <a href="pcc2:teams">Teams</a>, <a href="pcc2:allies">Alliances</a>, <a href="pcc2:simopts">Options</a>.</di>
      </dl>
    </page>


    <!-- Fleet Cost Comparison -->
    <page id="pcc2:fleetcost">
      <h1>Fleet Cost Comparison</h1>
      <p>This window displays the costs of each player's simulated fleet.
        Because not all costs are spent for just this one battle, you can use the options dialog to configure what to include.
        You need at least one ship in the simulation to access this dialog.
        The overview always includes the costs for building the actual ships and their weapons.</p>
      <kl>
        <ki key="Tab, Shift-Tab">Cycle through players or teams;</ki>
        <ki key="O"><a href="pcc2:fleetcostopts">Options</a>;</ki>
        <ki key="E"><a href="pcc2:export">Export list into a file</a>.</ki>
      </kl>

      <h2>Reference</h2>
      <dl>
        <di term="Keys:"> <kbd>Ctrl-C</kbd> from <a href="pcc2:bsim">battle simulator</a>.</di>
      </dl>
    </page>

    <!-- Fleet Cost Comparison Options -->
    <page id="pcc2:fleetcostopts">
      <h1>Fleet Cost Comparison Options</h1>
      <p>This dialog allows you to fine-tune the options for the <a href="pcc2:fleetcost">fleet cost comparison</a>.</p>
      <kl>
        <ki key="F">Toggle whether fighters are counted as if built using the <tt>lfm</tt> friendly code (<tt>ShipFighterCost</tt>),
          on a starbase (<tt>BaseFighterCost</tt>), or not at all;</ki>
        <ki key="T">Toggle whether torpedo costs are included;</ki>
        <ki key="E">Toggle whether engine costs are included;
          Note that engine costs for custom ships are not included because we don't know how many engines these ships have;</ki>
        <ki key="P">Toggle whether planet defense costs are included;</ki>
        <ki key="B">Toggle whether costs for building a starbase, its defense,
          its fighters, and, if <kbd>T</kbd> is enabled and starbases actually use torpedoes in combat, its torpedoes are included;</ki>
        <ki key="L">Toggle whether starbase tech levels (beams, and torpedoes if appropriate) are included;</ki>
        <ki key="S">Toggle whether tech levels used for building ships are included.
          You can include tech levels once per ship (as if each ship was built on a different base specifically equipped to build this ship),
          or once per player (as if all ships were built on the same base; tech levels are billed to the first ship needing them);</ki>
        <ki key="Y">Toggle whether costs are grouped by player or by team.</ki>
      </kl>

      <h2>Reference</h2>
      <dl>
        <di term="Keys:"> <kbd>O</kbd> from <a href="pcc2:fleetcost">fleet cost comparison</a>.</di>
      </dl>
    </page>

    <!-- Simulator Result -->
    <page id="pcc2:simresult">
      <h1>Battle Simulator Result</h1>

      <p>When starting the simulation, the simulator will compute one possible outcome and show you the simulation result screen.
        You can run more simulations from here.</p>
      <p>The simulator result screen displays simulation results.
        The "Totals" tab has results grouped by class and probability (e.g. "2 Feds surviving: 10x, 1 Borg surviving: 2x").
        The "Details" tab has information about each unit.</p>

      <kl>
        <ki key="Space">Run one simulation;</ki>
        <ki key="S">Run one series. With <a href="pcc2:simopts">seed control</a> enabled, this will simulate all possible results exactly once. A second series will yield the same result as the first one. Otherwise, just simulates 110 random battles;</ki>
        <ki key="R">Repeat indefinitely, until canceled with a key;</ki>
        <ki key="Enter">From totals tab, <a href="pcc2:vcr">watch sample battle</a> that produces this result;</ki>
        <ki key="E">From details tab, close result screen and place cursor on current ship;</ki>
        <ki key="ESC">Exit.</ki>
      </kl>

      <p>Clicking on a number on the "Details" tab will let you <a href="pcc2:vcr">watch a sample battle</a> that yields the minimum or maximum result for that value, respectively.</p>

      <h2>Reference</h2>
      <dl>
        <di term="Keys:"> <kbd>Enter</kbd> from <a href="pcc2:bsim">battle simulator</a>.</di>
      </dl>
    </page>

    <!-- VCR -->
    <page id="pcc2:vcr">
      <h1>VCR</h1>
      <p>The VCR allows you to view this turn's battles or, when invoked from the <a href="pcc2:simresult">battle simulator</a>, simulated fights.</p>
      <p>Choose a fight using arrows, press <kbd>Enter</kbd> to play it. In addition, the following keys are available:</p>
      <kl>
        <ki key="Tab">Display combat diagram. This can give you an overview over big fights. All units come in as color-coded lines at the left; destruction and owner change is displayed with appropriate symbols and color changes.
        <kl>
          <ki key="T">Toggle team colors. By default, lines are colored by owner. With this option enabled, they are colored by <a href="pcc2:teams">teams</a>;</ki>
          <ki key="S">Combat score summary. Shows how much experience and build points each race got this turn, and how many tons they sunk;</ki>
        </kl></ki>
        <ki key="S">Combat score summary;</ki>
        <ki key="L, R"><a href="pcc2:vcrinfo">Display information about one side of the fight</a>;</ki>
        <ki key="F4">Show location of fight on <a href="pcc2:starchart">starchart</a>, if position is known;</ki>
        <ki key="Enter">Watch fight. See <a href="pcc2:vcr:playback">Classic Playback</a> and <a href="pcc2:flak">FLAK playback</a>.</ki>
      </kl>

      <h2>Display Layout</h2>

      <p>The first line shows the number of the battle on the left.
        On the right, it shows the battle format (e.g. "PHost 4"), the position of the fight if known,
        and the random-number seed ("#12345").</p>

      <p>For fights with two participants, the dialog shows the details for both.
        For fights with more participants, depending on available space, shows the names of the participants, a summary of the fleets ("10 Rebel ships"),
        or a summary of participating players ("10 Rebels, 5 Colonies").
        In that case, use <kbd>L</kbd> to see details.</p>

      <h2>Reference</h2>
      <dl>
        <di term="Keys:"> <kbd>V</kbd> from <a href="pcc2:racescreen">race screen</a>,
          <kbd>Enter</kbd> from <a href="pcc2:simresult">simulator result</a>.</di>
      </dl>
    </page>

    <!-- VCR Playback -->
    <page id="pcc2:vcr:playback">
      <h1>VCR Playback</h1>
      <p>This screen displays a classic, 1:1 fight.
        On the top, you see the two fighting units.
        On the bottom, you see each unit's status (shields, damage, weapon status).</p>

      <kl>
        <ki key="Right">Play&#47;pause;</ki>
        <ki key="Shift-Right, Shift-Left">Move single frame;</ki>
        <ki key="Shift-B">Move backward single frame;</ki>
        <ki key="Shift-F">Move forward single frame;</ki>
        <ki key="Ctrl-Right, Ctrl-Left">Move 20 frames;</ki>
        <ki key="Alt-Right, Alt-Left">Go to end&#47;beginning;</ki>
        <ki key="ESC">Exit.</ki>
      </kl>

      <h2>Reference</h2>
      <dl>
        <di term="Keys:"> <kbd>Enter</kbd> from <a href="pcc2:vcr">VCR selection</a>.</di>
      </dl>
    </page>


    <!-- VCR Info -->
    <page id="pcc2:vcrinfo">
      <h1>Combat Information</h1>
      <p>This window displays information about combatants.
        For classic combat, shows one participant, use <kbd>Tab</kbd> to switch sides.
        For FLAK combat, shows the fleet structure on the left side, use <kbd>&#x2191;</kbd> and <kbd>&#x2193;</kbd> to browse.</p>

      <p>When looking at a ship, PCC2 compares its arms with the permitted maximum for its type (e.g. "4 beams, hull allows 6").
        In classic combat, the type is not always exactly known; in this case, PCC2 offers a list of possible types.</p>

      <p>When looking at a planet, PCC2 tries to find out whether it has a starbase, and how many defense posts it has.</p>
      <kl>
        <ki key="Tab">(classic) Switch to other side;</ki>
        <ki key="S">Show ship <a href="pcc2:specsheet">specification sheet</a> for current ship;</ki>
        <ki key="Ins">Add this unit to the <a href="pcc2:bsim">battle simulation</a>. This uses the unit's state after the fight, and is not possible when the unit was destroyed;</ki>
        <ki key="Shift-Ins">Add this unit to the battle simulation, using the unit's state before the fight.</ki>
      </kl>

      <h2>Reference</h2>
      <dl>
        <di term="Keys:"> <kbd>L</kbd> and <kbd>R</kbd> from <a href="pcc2:vcr">VCR selection</a></di>
      </dl>
    </page>

    <!-- FLAK playback -->
    <page id="pcc2:flak">
      <h1>FLAK Playback</h1>
      <p>This is the FLAK player that displays fleet combat.</p>
      <p>FLAK has two display modes:</p>
      <ul>
        <!-- FIXME: missing <li>Isometric 3-D. Shows the battle at a 45 degree angle with no perspective;</li> -->
        <li>Perspective 3-D. Shows the battle from a freely-moving camera with proper perspective;</li>
        <li>Flat view. Shows the a flat view onto the battle from the top.
          Since FLAK is just two-dimensional internally, this is what the combat engine actually does.</li>
      </ul>
      <p>Most of the screen is covered by the playback arena.
        On the right, you see a list of all participating fleets and units.</p>
      <p>During playback, use the following keys:</p>
      <kl>
        <ki key="Right">Start/pause playback;</ki>
        <ki key="Up, Down">Scroll in ship list</ki>
        <ki key="Ctrl-&#x2190;">Rewind 20 seconds;</ki>
        <ki key="Ctrl-&#x2192;">Fast-forward 20 seconds;</ki>
        <ki key="Alt-&#x2190;">Rewind to beginning;</ki>
        <ki key="Alt-&#x2192;">Fast-forward to end;</ki>
        <ki key="Shift-B">Rewind one second;</ki>
        <ki key="Shift-F">Forward one second;</ki>
        <ki key="3, Tab">Toggle display mode;</ki>
        <!-- FIXME: missing <ki key="1, 2">Show status of currently-selected ship on left/right info panel;</ki> -->
        <ki key="F">(perspective mode) Camera follows current fleet;</ki>
        <ki key="C">Toggle automatic camera;</ki>
        <ki key="Shift-Arrow">(perspective mode) Move camera;</ki>
        <ki key="A">Zoom in;</ki>
        <ki key="Z, Y">Zoom out.</ki>
      </kl>
      <h2>Reference</h2>
      <dl>
        <di term="Keys:"> <kbd>Enter</kbd> from <a href="pcc2:vcr">VCR selection</a> for FLAK fight.</di>
      </dl>
    </page>

    <!-- FCode dialog (all of them) -->
    <page id="pcc2:fcode">
      <h1>Friendly Code</h1>
      <p>Ships and planets have a Friendly Code, which is a three-character password that serves as access control,
        and can trigger special actions.</p>
      <p>As a little help, PCC2 knows special friendly codes and offers you them on a list.</p>
      <kl>
        <ki key="Tab">Switch between input and list;</ki>
        <ki key="Alt-R">Pick a random friendly code that has no special meaning.</ki>
      </kl>

      <p>Note that the list also contains a few codes that are not at all special, but should be used with care.
        For example, Host lets Lizard ships start with "BBB"; you should change this to avoid your enemies guessing it.
        The friendly code <tt>???</tt> is used by the <a href="pcc2:bsim">simulator</a> as an exception to the
        "same fcode, no fight" rule, so you don't have to come up with individual fcodes for completely made-up fights.</p>

      <h2>Reference</h2>
      <dl>
        <di term="Keys:"> <kbd>F</kbd> from <a href="pcc2:cscreen">control screens</a>
          and <a href="pcc2:bsim">battle simulator</a>.</di>
      </dl>
    </page>

    <!-- Visual Scan -->
    <page id="pcc2:listship">
      <h1>List Ships</h1>

      <p>This window displays information about enemy or own ships.
        It is used as visual scanner, and to select ships for various operations.</p>
        <kl>
          <ki key="Up&#47;Down">Browse through ships;</ki>
          <ki key="Ctrl-Up&#47;Ctrl-Down">Browse through marked ships;</ki>
          <ki key=".">Mark&#47;unmark current ship;</ki>
          <ki key="C"><a href="pcc2:cargo">Cargo transfer</a> for own ships; last known cargo for foreign ships;</ki>
          <ki key="Ctrl-C">Show cargo summary for all your ships on the list;</ki>
          <ki key="Enter">Go to this ship in <a href="pcc2:shipscreen">ship screen</a>;</ki>
          <ki key="R">Allow&#47;forbid&#47;request&#47;drop remote control (PHost feature);</ki>
          <ki key="S">Toggle specification display (a window similar to regular <a href="pcc2:specsheet">specification display</a> which automatically updates as you browse ships);</ki>
          <ki key="L">Toggle list view;</ki>
          <ki key="Shift-M">Show <a href="pcc2:msgin">subspace messages</a> from this ship;</ki>
          <ki key="Ins">Add this ship to the <a href="pcc2:bsim">battle simulation</a>;</ki>
          <ki key="Ctrl-Ins">Add all ships to the <a href="pcc2:bsim">battle simulation</a>.</ki>
        </kl>

        <p>When you have opened the list view using <kbd>L</kbd>,
          you can use the right mouse button or <kbd>#</kbd> resp. <kbd>\</kbd>
          to bring up a menu that allows you to sort the list.
          The sort order will be saved, and also be used for other "ships at one place" lists,
          including the order for the <kbd>Tab</kbd> key on the <a href="pcc2:shipscreen">Ship Screen</a>.</p>

        <h2>Current vs. Prediction</h2>

        <p>By default, this window displays ships at a particular location;
          the cargo summary will display current cargo.</p>

        <p>When this window is invoked with <kbd>Ctrl-N</kbd>, it predicts future positions of your ships.
          From a planet, it will display ships that will be at this planet.
          From a ship, it will display ships that will be at the same location as that ship next turn.
          Unlike regular fuel consumption computation, this prediction resolves intercepts.
          Cargo summary will show predicted cargo.</p>

        <h2>Reference</h2>
        <dl>
          <di term="Keys:"> <kbd>L</kbd> from <a href="pcc2:cscreen">control screens</a>
            and <a href="pcc2:starchart">starchart</a> (current ships),
            <kbd>Ctrl-N</kbd> from <a href="pcc2:cscreen">control screens</a>
            and <a href="pcc2:starchart">starchart</a> (predicted positions);</di>
          <di term="Related command:"><a href="int:name:ui.listships">UI.ListShips</a>,
            <a href="int:name:ui.listshipprediction">UI.ListShipPrediction</a>.</di>
        </dl>
    </page>

    <!-- Specification -->
    <page id="pcc2:specsheet">
      <h1>Ship Specification</h1>
      <p>This window displays information about a ship's hull.
        It lists resources needed to build the ship, as well as its cargo capacity and special functions.</p>
      <kl>
        <ki key="ESC">Close window;</ki>
        <ki key="W">Show weapon effects against this ship;</ki>
        <ki key="F1">Browse ship abilities.</ki>
      </kl>

      <h2>Ship abilities</h2>
      <p>Ships can have special abilities, such as Cloak or Gravitonic.</p>
      <p>PCC2 uses the PHost&nbsp;4 ship abilities internally.
        Even when you're using a game not hosted by PHost&nbsp;4, ships will have <em>Tow</em> when they can tow,
        or <em>Full Weaponry</em> when they belong to the Feds.</p>
      <p>Abilities available to all ships are considered <em>racial abilities</em>.
        Those are not shown on the normal specification sheet, but listed on the ability list you can show with <kbd>F1</kbd>.</p>

      <h3>Ability Icons</h3>
      <p>On the Specification Sheet and on the <a href="pcc2:buildship">Ship Build Screen</a>,
        ship abilities are normally shown as a set of icons.
        The color of the icon shows the status of the ability.</p>
      <ul class="compact">
        <li>Colored icon: you have the ability;</li>
        <li>Red icon: you have the ability, but it is damaged and can currently not be used;</li>
        <li>Gray icon: you cannot use the ability.
          A green marker indicates that you will be able to use the ability at a higher experience level.
          A red marker indicates that only other players can use the ability.</li>
      </ul>
      <p>If you prefer the abilities to be shown as text, use the
        <a href="pcc2:settings">Settings Menu</a>, Preferences > User Interface > Ship ability icons.</p>

      <h3>Ability List</h3>
      <p>Use <kbd>F1</kbd> from the specification sheet to pop up the detailed ability list.
        This list uses various icons to tell you about an ability's status:</p>
      <ul class="compact">
        <li><tt>[U]</tt> is a universal ability, which every player has on every ship;</li>
        <li><tt>[R]</tt> is a racial ability, which some players have on each of their ships;</li>
        <li><tt>[G]</tt> is a general class ability, which every ship of this type has for every player;</li>
        <li><tt>[C]</tt> is a class ability, every ship of this type has for some players;</li>
        <li><tt>[S]</tt> is a ship ability, which this individual ship has, no matter who owns it.</li>
      </ul>
      <p>In addition, a symbol tells you whether you have this ability:</p>
      <ul class="compact">
        <li><tt>&#x25B6;</tt> you have it; shown in <font color="red">red</font> if it is damaged</li>
        <li><tt>+</tt> you need more experience;</li>
        <li><tt>-</tt> your experience is too high (maybe you now have a better ability);</li>
        <li>(blank) this ability is only available to other players.</li>
      </ul>

      <h2>Reference</h2>
      <dl>
        <di term="Keys:"> <kbd>S</kbd> from <a href="pcc2:shipscreen">ship screen</a>,
          <a href="pcc2:listship">ship list</a>, <a href="pcc2:buildship">ship build screen</a>, or
          <a href="pcc2:vcrinfo">VCR details screen</a>.</di>
      </dl>
    </page>

    <!-- Navigation starchart -->
    <page id="pcc2:navchart">
      <h1>Navigation Chart</h1>
      <p>The Navigation Chart shows the surroundings of the current ship.
        It can be zoomed and moved, and thus be used to set up waypoints farther away than the normal scanner chart allows.</p>
      <p>If the ship is moving, the map displays a set of warp circles around its position.
        For a ship that is hyperdriving, circles will be shown at 340&nbsp;ly and 360&nbsp;ly distance.</p>
      <kl>
        <ki key="Arrows">Move around in steps of 10. Hold <kbd>Shift</kbd> to go a single light year, <kbd>Ctrl</kbd> to go 100;</ki>
        <ki key="Alt-R">Move cursor by random amount +&#47;-&nbsp;5 in either direction;</ki>
        <ki key="+, -">Zoom;</ki>
        <ki key="Z">Enter zoom level manually;</ki>
        <ki key="Space">Lock onto planet;</ki>
        <ki key="Enter">Lock onto ship;</ki>
        <ki key="Tab">Recenter map at current position;</ki>
        <ki key="Ins">Add secondary set of warp circles at current position;</ki>
        <ki key="Backspace">Undo last <kbd>Tab</kbd>;</ki>
        <ki key="C">(only on capable ships) toggle Chunnel mode. When enabled, only possible Chunnel targets can be selected, and PCC2 will set up a chunnel when you confirm this dialog;</ki>
        <ki key="L"><a href="pcc2:listship">List ships</a>;</ki>
        <ki key="digit M, Ctrl-M">Create canned marker. <kbd>Ctrl-M</kbd> creates a default marker, <kbd>1 M</kbd> through <kbd>9 M</kbd> create markers 1-9;</ki>
        <ki key="F5"><a href="pcc2:envscreen">Planet information</a>;</ki>
        <ki key="F10">Confirm.</ki>
      </kl>

      <p>You can use <kbd>Alt</kbd>+letter to toggle starchart options,
        e.g. <kbd>Alt-M</kbd> to toggle display of minefields.
        See <a href="pcc2:starchart">Starchart, section "Option Toggles"</a> for details.</p>

      <h2>Reference</h2>
      <dl>
        <di term="Keys:"> <kbd>A</kbd> from <a href="pcc2:shipscreen">ship screen</a> or <a href="pcc2:fleetscreen">fleet screen</a>.</di>
      </dl>
    </page>

    <!-- Cargo Transfer -->
    <page id="pcc2:cargo">
      <h1>Cargo Transfer</h1>
      <p>After choosing the target (if applicable), the Cargo Transfer window displays the unit you started with on the left, and the target on the right.</p>
      <kl>
        <ki key="&#x2191;, &#x2193;">Choose kind of cargo to transfer;</ki>
        <ki key="&#x2190;, &#x2192;">Move 10 units. With <a href="prefixarg">prefix argument</a>, move that many;</ki>
        <ki key="Shift-&#x2190;, Shift-&#x2192;">Move 1 unit;</ki>
        <ki key="Ctrl-&#x2190;, Ctrl-&#x2192;">Move 100 units;</ki>
        <ki key="Alt-&#x2190;, Alt-&#x2192;">Move as much as possible. With <a href="prefixarg">prefix</a>, move as many to make the left&#47;right unit have exactly that many;</ki>
        <ki key="U">If one unit is a planet, unload all T&#47;D&#47;M&#47;$&#47;Sup&#47;Colonists to it;</ki>
        <ki key="S">If one unit is a planet, toggle automatic supply sale. Supplies you move off one unit appear as megacredits on the other;</ki>
        <ki key="O">Turn on overload mode, see below;</ki>
        <ki key="Enter">Confirm. Execute the transfer and close the window;</ki>
        <ki key="ESC">Cancel.</ki>
      </kl>

      <h2>Special Situations</h2>

      <p>You can <b>transfer cargo</b> to unowned or enemy units, or jettison into space.
        Unlike transfers to own units, which happen immediately, these orders will be executed during the host run.
        If you change your mind, you can get your cargo back by using the Cargo Transfer function again, and just loading it back.
        As an indicator for an active Transfer/Unload/Jettison order, a "&#x2192;" icon will appear next to the "C" button.</p>

      <p>PHost supports a <b>Beam up Multiple</b> mission.
        With this mission, you can beam up cargo from unowned or friendly planets.
        Unlike for the normal "Beam up Fuel", "Beam up Tritanium", etc. missions, you can choose the amounts you want to get.
        PCC2 allows you to set up such a transfer using the regular cargo transfer interface.
        Although the cargo transfer dialog will show the beamed-up cargo, it will not appear directly.
        Cargo will be beamed up when host runs.
        As an indicator for an active Beam Up Multiple order, a "&#x2190;" icon will appear next to the "C" button.</p>

      <h2>Overload Mode</h2>

      <p>Normally, PCC2 will not allow you to load more cargo onto a ship than will fit.
        You can turn off these checks using Overload Mode.
        This is useful in some rare situations.
        For example, you might want to beam up large amounts of cargo and let host decide how much you get.
        An alternative example would be two fully-loaded ships trying to swap some cargo.</p>

      <p>If you use Overload Mode, you need to manually make sure your ships are not overloaded.
        If you fail to do so, host will destroy your excess cargo.</p>

      <h2>Reference</h2>
      <dl>
        <di term="Keys:"> <kbd>C</kbd> and <kbd>U</kbd> from <a href="pcc2:cscreen">control screens</a> and <a href="pcc2:listship">visual scan</a>;</di>
        <di term="See also:"> <a href="pcc2:sellsup">Sell Supplies</a>.</di>
      </dl>
    </page>

    <!-- Multi-Ship Cargo Transfer -->
    <page id="pcc2:multicargo">
      <h1>Multi-Ship Cargo Transfer</h1>
      <p>This function allows you to transfer cargo between multiple units at once.
        For example, you can use it to distribute fuel or ammo between your fleet.</p>

        <p>PCC will ask for the cargo type to transfer.
          It will then display a list of all units that can carry this cargo.</p>

        <p>Cargo is transferred through a <b>hold space</b>, i.e. you can move cargo into the hold space and from there onto other units.
          In addition, one unit (usually, the planet) can be tagged as extension of the hold space:
          when you try to load cargo from hold space, but it is empty, it is taken from there;
          when you close this dialog but still have cargo in hold space, it is moved there.</p>

        <kl>
          <ki key="&#x2190;, +">Move 10 kt from hold space to this unit. With <a href="prefixarg">prefix argument</a>, move that many. With <kbd>Shift</kbd>, move 1. With <kbd>Ctrl</kbd>, move 100. With <kbd>Alt</kbd>, move everything;</ki>
          <ki key="&#x2192;, -">Move 10 kt from this unit to hold space. Modifiers like for <kbd>+</kbd> can be used;</ki>
          <ki key="Space, .">Tag current unit as extension to hold space, or untag it;</ki>
          <ki key="U">Unload all units (except for tagged unit) to hold space;</ki>
          <ki key="#">Menu. This menu's items distribute cargo from hold space to all units (except for the tagged unit) according to different rules.
            You can also call these functions by hitting their letter directly, without going through the menu.
            Functions are only available if hold space is not empty.
            <kl>
              <ki key="E">Distribute cargo evenly. Every unit receives the same amount;</ki>
              <ki key="F">Distribute free space evenly. Fill up all units until all have the same amount of free space;</ki>
              <ki key="P">Distribute proportionally. Give each unit cargo proportionally to their capacity;</ki>
            </kl>
          Note that neither of these functions will remove cargo from a unit;</ki>
          <ki key="A, Ins">Create temporary storage. You can use this to temporarily store cargo, which simplifies some maneuvers. The temporary storage must be empty before the cargo transfer can be confirmed. Up to 5 temporary storages can be created.</ki>
        </kl>

        <h2>Reference</h2>
        <dl>
          <di term="Keys:"> <kbd>D</kbd> from <a href="pcc2:shipscreen">ship screen</a>.</di>
        </dl>
    </page>

    <!-- Structure building -->
    <page id="pcc2:buildings">
      <h1>Buildings</h1>
      <p>You can build mines, factories, and defense posts on your planets.</p>
      <p>PCC2 offers three views. On each you can build a different selection of structures, and you see a different amount of useful information:</p>
      <ul>
        <li>Planetary Economy: build mines, factories, and defense;</li>
        <li>Mining Industry: build mines. Shows the predicted minerals mined by your mines;</li>
        <li>Defense: build planetary and starbase defense. Shows the resulting weapon strength.</li>
      </ul>

      <h2>Keys</h2>
      <kl>
        <ki key="&#x2191;, &#x2193;">Choose type of building;</ki>
        <ki key="&#x2190;, &#x2192;, Tab">Choose view;</ki>
        <ki key="+">Build one structure (with prefix: build that many);</ki>
        <ki key="-">Scrap one structure (with prefix: scrap that many). You can only scrap what you've built this turn;</ki>
        <ki key="T"><a href="pcc2:taxes">Taxes</a>;</ki>
        <ki key="S"><a href="pcc2:sellsup">Sell supplies</a>;</ki>
        <ki key="A"><a href="pcc2:autobuild">Auto build</a>;</ki>
        <ki key="G">Edit autobuild goals;</ki>
        <ki key="C">(defense) Show ground combat strength;</ki>
        <ki key="Enter">Confirm;</ki>
        <ki key="ESC">Cancel.</ki>
      </kl>

      <h2>Reference</h2>
      <dl>
        <di term="Keys:"> <kbd>B</kbd>, <kbd>D</kbd>, <kbd>M</kbd> from <a href="pcc2:planetscreen">planet screen</a>,
          <kbd>D</kbd> from <a href="pcc2:basescreen">starbase screen</a>.</di>
      </dl>
    </page>

    <!-- Taxation -->
    <page id="pcc2:taxes">
      <h1>Taxes</h1>
      <p>You can ask taxes from your natives and colonists.
        PCC2 shows the effect of taxation on your populations regarding income, happiness, growth, and experience.</p>
      <kl>
        <ki key="Tab">Switch between colonists and natives;</ki>
        <ki key="+, &#x2190;">Increase taxes (with prefix: by that amount);</ki>
        <ki key="-, &#x2190;">Decrease taxes (with prefix: by that amount);</ki>
        <ki key="Shift-&#x2192;">Pick lowest tax rate that gives a higher income (useful on small outposts);</ki>
        <ki key="Shift-&#x2190;">Pick highest tax rate that gives a lower income;</ki>
        <ki key="Ctrl-&#x2192;">Set tax rate 100%;</ki>
        <ki key="Ctrl-&#x2190;">Set tax rate 0%;</ki>
        <ki key="Space">Auto tax colonists and natives;</ki>
        <ki key="Shift-Space">Auto tax only current area (colonists or natives);</ki>
        <ki key="U, Backspace">Undo current area (revert to value when dialog was opened);</ki>
        <ki key="R">Toggle whether the population prediction displays absolute values (default), absolute or relative (percentage) per-turn change.
          With <kbd>Shift</kbd>, toggles between absolute and relative change only;</ki>
        <ki key="W">Change number of hissers or terraformers for prediction ("how would growth change if I had a heater here?");</ki>
        <ki key="=, %">(with prefix) Set tax rate to specified value.</ki>
      </kl>

      <p>The <em>Auto Tax</em> function implements "safe-taxing": it will aim at making the happiness 100% within 5..10 turns.
        If several tax rates yield the same income, it will use the lowest of them for greater population growth.
        This taxation algorithm is safe because it will not cause riots, not even if you lose a turn.
        However, other taxation algorithms are known which can yield higher income in many situations (e.g. "growth-taxing").</p>

      <h2>Prediction Effects</h2>

      <p>If you have ships, or ships performing the Hiss mission, their effect will be included in happiness and growth predictions.
        Using <kbd>W</kbd>, you can change the number of ships for the computation.
        Select a field using <kbd>&#x2191;</kbd>/<kbd>&#x2193;</kbd>, and use <kbd>&#x2190;</kbd>/<kbd>&#x2192;</kbd>, or type a number.</p>

      <h2>Reference</h2>
      <dl>
        <di term="Keys:"> <kbd>T</kbd> from <a href="pcc2:planetscreen">planet screen</a>.</di>
      </dl>
    </page>

    <!-- Sell supplies -->
    <page id="pcc2:sellsup">
      <h1>Sell Supplies</h1>

      <p>You can sell supplies to get money.</p>

      <p>With PCC, this is rarely needed because PCC automatically sells supplies when needed for buying something,
        and you can sell supplies during <a href="pcc2:cargo">cargo transfer</a>,
        but sometimes can still be useful.</p>

      <p>The "Sell Supplies" dialog will ask you how many supplies you want to sell.
        It will sell the supplies when you confirm with <kbd>Enter</kbd>.
        You can also enter the number of supplies you want to keep and confirm with <kbd>A</kbd>.</p>

      <p>The "Undo Supply Sale" dialog will ask you how many supplies you want to buy.
        You can only buy back supplies that you sold this turn, when you have not yet used the money.</p>

      <h2>Reference</h2>
      <dl>
        <di term="Keys:"> <kbd>S</kbd> (sell) and <kbd>Ctrl-S</kbd> (undo) from <a href="pcc2:planetscreen">planet screen</a>.</di>
      </dl>
    </page>

    <!-- Auto Build Goals -->
    <page id="pcc2:autobuild">
      <h1>Auto Build</h1>

      <p>PCC can automatically build structures for you.
        You can define goals (number fo structures) and speeds for each planet.</p>

      <p>When ordered to perform automatic building, PCC2 will sort those values by speed, highest first.
        It will then try to build as many structures as the speed says, stopping only when the goal has been reached or rules don't allow building more.
        It will then proceed with the second structure, etc.
        If all structures have been processed, the cycle starts again, until nothing more can be built.
        As a special exception, PCC2 will make sure there's at least one factory, even if you ordered it to build mines first.</p>

      <p>By default, goals are 1000 (meaning "infinite"), and speeds are 5 for mines, 10 for factories, and 3 for defense posts.
        This means that auto build will try to build 10 factories, then 5 mines, then 3 defense posts.
        If you have lots of money, this means that PCC2 will build twice as many factories as mines.
        If you have little money, this means PCC2 will first build up factories before starting with mines.</p>

      <p>To disable auto build for one structure, set its goals and&#47;or speeds to zero.</p>

      <h2>Reference</h2>
      <dl>
        <di term="Keys:"> <kbd>G</kbd> and <kbd>A</kbd> from <a href="pcc2:buildings">build screen</a>,
          and as options on <a href="pcc2:globact">global actions</a>.</di>
      </dl>
    </page>

    <!-- Build ships -->
    <page id="pcc2:buildship">
      <h1>Building Ships</h1>

      <p>You can build ships on your starbases.
        You set up the ship design using the ship build dialog.
        The ship will be built during the next host run and available next turn
        (or later, when the ship limit is reached and the build queue is active).</p>

      <p>The ship build dialog is also used for the related functions,</p>
      <ul>
        <li>Ship Cost Calculator to compute costs for any fictional ship;</li>
        <li>Editing "EnqueueShip" commands for auto tasks.</li>
      </ul>

      <p>The dialog has four tabs.
        Choose the hull type on the first tab, further components on the other three tabs.
        You can choose components you don't yet have the right tech for, PCC2 will then include the tech level
        cost in the bill displayed below, and automatically upgrade tech as appropriate.
        For beams and torpedoes, you can choose how many components to put into your ship using <kbd>+</kbd> and <kbd>-</kbd>.</p>

      <p>Available keys vary depending on the exact use of the dialog.</p>
      <kl>
        <ki key="Enter">Confirm build; modifies the build order to build this ship. If you do not have enough resources to build this ship, offers to put the build order onto the <a href="pcc2:basetaskscreen">starbase auto task</a>;</ki>
        <ki key="ESC">Return to previous screen, do not change the build order;</ki>
        <ki key="C">Cancel current build order;</ki>
        <ki key="U">Toggle whether parts from starbase storage will be used;</ki>
        <ki key="I">Toggle whether tech upgrades are included in the cost computation;</ki>
        <ki key="D">Display detailed bill listing all components, their cost, and the remaining/missing resources on the planet;</ki>
        <ki key="S">Show <a href="pcc2:specsheet">hull specification sheet</a>;</ki>
        <ki key="Space">Build or scrap individual components (for Super Refit).</ki>
      </kl>

      <h2>Reference</h2>
      <dl>
        <di term="Keys:"> <kbd>B</kbd> or <kbd>S</kbd> from <a href="pcc2:buildings">build screen</a>,
          <kbd>E</kbd> from <a href="pcc2:shiptaskscreen">ship auto task screen</a>.</di>
      </dl>
    </page>

    <!-- Build Queue Manager -->
    <page id="pcc2:queuemanager">
      <h1>Manage Build Queue</h1>
      <p>This window displays all your current <a href="pcc2:buildship">ship build orders</a> and allows you to assign build priorities ("PBx" friendly codes).</p>
      <p>For each build order, it displays:</p>
      <ul>
        <li>Type of ship being built, and name of the starbase building the ship;</li>
        <li>Friendly code. Highlighted in red if there are multiple orders with the same PBx friendly code;</li>
        <li>Position of the build order in the build queue, if known (1=first);</li>
        <li>Number of build points consumed by this build order, if known/applicable.
          For example, "3 / 21" means you have 21 build points and this ship consumes 3.
          The next line might be "5 / 18", saying that you have 18 points remaining, consuming 5.
          The number consumed is shown in red if you do not have enough points.</li>
      </ul>
      <p>The list is shown in approximate order the ships will be built, first ships first (highest priority, PB1).
        Scroll around using the arrows, or use the following keys:</p>
      <kl>
        <ki key="+, Shift-&#x2191;">Increase this build order's priority (build earlier);</ki>
        <ki key="-, Shift-&#x2193;">Decrease this build order's priority (build later);</ki>
        <ki key="1..9">Set friendly code of starbase to PBx;</ki>
        <ki key="0">(zero) Remove PBx friendly code;</ki>
        <ki key="S">Show summary of build orders by type and kind (see below);</ki>
        <ki key="G">Go to <a href="pcc2:basescreen">starbase screen</a> for current starbase
          (will ask whether to apply or discard changes);</ki>
        <ki key="Enter">Confirm and apply all changes;</ki>
        <ki key="ESC">Cancel and discard all changes.</ki>
      </kl>

      <h2>Notes</h2>

      <p>Build queue rules differ between host versions.
        The order shown is not necessarily exact.
        In particular, new build orders will be collected starting from an unknown/random starbase,
        so if you give two new orders, we cannot predict which will be built first.</p>
      <p>This dialog shows the PBx friendly codes first (PB1, then PB2, etc.),
        reflecting that those build orders will be processed first if you are awarded a priority build.
        Whether you are awarded a priority build or perform a regular build instead is decided by host
        (e.g. too few build points, fewer than 450 ships in game in HOST).</p>
      <p>PCC2 assumes you can have one order in the PB1 slot, one in the PB2 slot, and so on,
        and highlights duplicate codes as an error.
        This matches the PHost rule.
        In HOST, you can have multiple builds with the same code, but rules regarding this are complex
        and vary between versions, so it's better to stick to the simple rule.</p>
      <p>For PHost, this dialog also shows clone orders.
        In HOST, cloning uses entirely different rules than regular builds and are not shown here.</p>

      <h2>Planned Builds</h2>
      <p>On the <a href="pcc2:buildship">ship build screen</a>, you can try to build a ship even if you do not have sufficient resources.
        In that case, PCC2 will create an auto-task containing an <tt>EnqueueShip</tt> command.</p>
        <p>Such tasks will be shown as "Plan &lt;ship&gt;" on this list, with a Clock icon, and cannot be prioritized.</p>

      <h2>Summary</h2>
      <p>The <kbd>S</kbd> key ("Summary...") brings up a dialog showing a summary of type and kind of ship build orders:</p>
      <ul>
        <li>How many ships of type X are you building?</li>
        <li>How many ships are being built, cloned, or planned?</li>
      </ul>
      <p>This dialog does not allow any manipulation of the build orders.
        However, you can use the <kbd>M</kbd> ("Mark...") button to mark or unmark the respective starbases,
        to process them further later on.</p>

      <h2>Reference</h2>
      <dl>
        <di term="Keys:"> <kbd>Q</kbd> from <a href="pcc2:basescreen">starbase screen</a>.</di>
      </dl>
    </page>

    <!-- Drawing in the starchart -->
    <page id="pcc2:draw">
      <h1>Drawing</h1>
      <p>You can draw four kinds of items into the starchart:</p>
      <ul>
        <li>Polygons, sequences of lines;</li>
        <li>Rectangles;</li>
        <li>Circles;</li>
        <li>Markers, little symbols.</li>
      </ul>
      <p>If you want to draw a marker, PCC2 will prompt you for shape and color, and draw that marker
        into the starchart.
        For the other types, you'll be dropped back in the starchart, and a
        new shape starting here will be begun.
        Complete the shape and finish it with <kbd>ESC</kbd>.</p>
      <p>Regular starchart movement keys are accepted.</p>
      <kl>
        <ki key="+, -">(circle) Change radius in steps of 10. With <a href="prefixarg">prefix</a>, that many. With <kbd>Shift</kbd>, in steps of 1;</ki>
        <ki key="Y">(circle) Make radius 350 ly;</ki>
        <ki key="=">(circle) With <a href="prefixarg">prefix</a>: make it that large;</ki>
        <ki key="W">(circle) With <a href="prefixarg">prefix</a>: make it X&#xb2; ly large (distance covered with warp factor);</ki>
        <ki key="G">(circle) With <a href="prefixarg">prefix</a>: make it 2&#xd7;X&#xb2; ly large (distance covered with gravitonic engine);</ki>
        <ki key="C">Change color;</ki>
        <ki key="T">Change <a href="pcc2:drawtag">tag</a>;</ki>
        <ki key="Alt">(circle) Hold <kbd>Alt</kbd> while moving the mouse to set the circle radius;</ki>
        <ki key="+">(line) Finish line and start next one;</ki>
        <ki key="Backspace">Go back to starting point;</ki>
        <ki key="X">(line, rectangle) Swap start and end point;</ki>
        <ki key="Del">Cancel, delete the drawing;</ki>
        <ki key="ESC">Finish.</ki>
      </kl>

      <h2>Reference</h2>
      <dl>
        <di term="Keys:"> <kbd>P</kbd> from <a href="pcc2:starchart">starchart</a>.</di>
      </dl>
    </page>

    <!-- Drawing tags -->
    <page id="pcc2:drawtag">
      <h1>Drawing Tags</h1>
      <p>Each <a href="pcc2:draw">drawing</a> can have a tag.
        You can use tags to group drawings thematically,
        e.g. different tags for borders, freighter routes, and enemy sightings.
        By default, all drawings are displayed, but you can filter display to show just one tag.</p>
      <p>A tag can be a number or string (technically: an <a href="int:name:atom">atom</a>).</p>

      <h2>Setting Drawing Tags</h2>
      <p>You can choose the tag for a new drawing using <kbd>T</kbd> on the <a href="pcc2:draw">Drawing</a> dialog.</p>
      <p>You can change a drawing's tag using <kbd>T</kbd> on the <a href="pcc2:starchart">starchart</a>.</p>
      <p>Both dialogs will let you enter a new tag, or choose an existing one from a list.
        When changing an existing line's tag, you can use <kbd>Alt-A</kbd>
        to change the tag of all adjacent lines as well.</p>

      <h2>Filtering Drawings</h2>
      <p>You can filter tags using <kbd>Alt-F</kbd> on the starchart.
        The dialog will let you select an existing tag and then display just that.
        Press <kbd>Alt-F</kbd> again to turn off the filter.</p>

      <h2>Reference</h2>
      <dl>
        <di term="Keys:"> <kbd>T</kbd> from <a href="pcc2:starchart">starchart</a>
          and <a href="pcc2:draw">Drawing</a> dialog; <kbd>Alt-F</kbd> from <a href="pcc2:starchart">starchart</a>.</di>
      </dl>
    </page>

    <!-- Starchart distance mode -->
    <page id="pcc2:distance">
      <h1>Distance Mode</h1>
      <p>Distance mode allows you to measure distances on the starchart.
        It behaves a little different when you invoke it from a ship you play, or from another context.
        When you invoke it from a ship, PCC2 automatically computes that ship's fuel consumption
        (as if you had typed <kbd>F</kbd>), and starts measuring at that ship's waypoint, not its position.
        Also, <kbd>ESC</kbd> will return to the ship instead of leaving you where you are.</p>
      <p>Regular starchart movement keys are accepted.</p>
      <kl>
        <ki key="X">Swap start and end point;</ki>
        <ki key="F">When looking at a ship, compute much fuel this ship would need to cover the requested distance.
          The ship doesn't have to currently be at the start or end point;</ki>
        <ki key="W">When a ship has been selected using <kbd>F</kbd>, and that ship is at the origin
          of the measurement, this sets its waypoint to the current position;</ki>
        <ki key="Backspace">Go back to starting point and exit distance meter;</ki>
        <ki key="ESC, D">Exit distance mode.</ki>
      </kl>

      <h2>Reference</h2>
      <dl>
        <di term="Keys:"> <kbd>D</kbd> from <a href="pcc2:starchart">starchart</a>.</di>
      </dl>
    </page>

    <!-- Global Actions -->
    <page id="pcc2:globact">
      <h1>Global Actions</h1>

      <p>Global actions allow you to perform an action on many objects (ships, planets) at once.</p>
      <p>On the left side, you can choose an action to perform.
        Actions are grouped in a tree, use <kbd>Space</kbd> or click the "+" to unfold a tree node.</p>
      <kl>
        <ki key="Enter">Execute selected action. This will normally display a dialog asking you for parameters or confirmation;</ki>
        <ki key="N">Toggle exclude numerical fcodes option. By default, this is enabled, so units with numerical friendly codes are excluded to leave your battle setups alone;</ki>
        <ki key="S">Toggle exclude special fcodes option. By default, this is enabled, so units with special friendly codes are excluded to not disturb your special missions;</ki>
        <ki key="M">Toggle marked objects only option. When enabled, only marked objects will be processed;</ki>
        <ki key="1,2">Toggle ships/planets. By default, this function operates on all units, but you can apply a global action to ships or planets only;</ki>
        <ki key="L">Toggle lock override. By default, this function tries to avoid, for example, changing waypoints of a ship that operates on an auto-waypoint, but you can force it to process those, too (although this may confuse the Auto Task);</ki>
        <ki key="F7">Search. This produces a new search result for <kbd>R</kbd> to work on;</ki>
        <ki key="R">Toggle search result option. When enabled, this function operates on the last search result. When disabled, Global Actions operate on all units;</ki>
        <ki key="ESC">Exit.</ki>
      </kl>

      <h2>Description of the Actions</h2>

      <dl>
        <di term="Friendly Codes">This item offers the ability to randomize affected friendly codes, or to <a href="pcc2:fcode">set to a particular value</a>;</di>
        <di term="Missions">This item allows you to change starbase missions, starship missions, and starship primary enemies.
          Note that not all starship missions are possible here: those that need to know the "current ship" cannot be set globally;</di>
        <di term="Building">This item allows you to set <a href="pcc2:autobuild">auto-build goals</a> on all planets, or perform auto-build. Note that goals can even be set on planets you don't own so you can pre-initialize them before actually colonizing them;</di>
        <di term="Taxes">This item has three "Optimize" choices, which will set optimum taxes (safetax) for Colonists, Natives, or both, respectively;</di>
        <di term="Export"><a href="pcc2:export">Export data</a> into various data formats. Note that this can only export planets or ships, not both at the same time;</di>
        <di term="Script Command">Allows you to enter a single-line script command which will be executed for each object. This is similar to using a <tt>ForEach</tt> command (with an <tt>If</tt> for the filtering) on the <a href="pcc2:console">console</a>. It differs in that this creates a process for each unit.</di>
      </dl>

      <p>In PCC2ng, plugins can provide additional global actions.</p>

      <h2>Reference</h2>
      <dl>
        <di term="Keys:"> <kbd>G</kbd> from <a href="pcc2:racescreen">race screen</a> or <a href="pcc2:search">search</a>.</di>
      </dl>
    </page>

    <!-- Export -->
    <page id="pcc2:export">
      <h1>Export</h1>

      <p>This dialog allows you to export data into various formats, both human-readable and machine-readable.
        The objects to export are selected in a previous step, usually, on the <a href="pcc2:globact">Global Action</a> dialog.
        Use this dialog to set the output format.</p>
      <kl>
        <ki key="Ins">Add a field;</ki>
        <ki key="Del">Remove a field;</ki>
        <ki key="Space">Edit current field;</ki>
        <ki key="Ctrl-&#x2191;/&#x2193;">Move a field up or down;</ki>
        <ki key="&#x2190;/&#x2192;, +/-">Change field width.
          The field width is used for text output formats.
          By default, PCC2 chooses a width, but you can override it by specifying one.
          These keys change the width by 10 or the <a href="prefixarg">prefix argument</a>,
          hold <kbd>Shift</kbd> to change by 1, hold <kbd>Ctrl</kbd> to change by 100.
          Positive values (shown as "&#x2192;NN") align the value to the right, which is typically used for numbers;
          negative values (shown as "NN&#x2190;") align the value to the left, which is typically used for text;</ki>
        <ki key="*">Toggle field alignment (left/right);</ki>
        <ki key="F">Change output file type;</ki>
        <ki key="C">Change output file character set;</ki>
        <ki key="Ctrl+S">Save settings into a file;</ki>
        <ki key="Ctrl+R">Read settings from a file;</ki>
        <ki key="Enter">Ask for output file name and do the export.</ki>
      </kl>

      <p>This feature is also available in the standalone <tt>c2export</tt> program.</p>

      <h2>Output File Formats</h2>

      <dl>
        <di term="Text file"> creates a plain text file;</di>
        <di term="Text table"> creates an ASCII-art table;</di>
        <di term="Comma-separated values"> and its siblings create a file that can be imported into a spreadsheet program. Field widths are ignored in this format;</di>
        <di term="JSON"> is the ubiquitous JavaScript-based data interchange format. Field widths are ignored in this format;</di>
        <di term="HTML table"> produces a HTML table that can be viewed with a browser or imported into a spreadsheet program;</di>
        <di term="dBASE file"> produces a binary database file format. This format can be imported by a number of spreadsheet or database programs.</di>
      </dl>

      <h2>Format of a Settings File</h2>

      <p>Settings are stored in text files.
        By convention, these files have the extension ".ccx".
        Settings files consist of lines of the form "name=value", much like <tt>pconfig.src</tt>.
        Empty lines and lines starting with "#" are ignored.</p>
      <ul>
        <li><b>Fields=NAME@WIDTH</b>: add a field. This line can occur multiple times to add multiple fields.
          The "@WIDTH" part is optional.
          You can also add multiple fields in one assignment by separating them with commas, as in "Fields=Name,Id";</li>
        <li><b>Charset=NAME</b>: select character set (optional);</li>
        <li><b>Format=FORMAT</b>: select ouput file type (optional);</li>
      </ul>

      <h2>Reference</h2>
      <dl>
        <di term="Keys:"> this function is accessible via <a href="pcc2:globact">global actions</a> to export ships/planets.
          It is also available using <kbd>E</kbd> on the
          <a href="pcc2:listship">List Ship</a> cargo summary,
          <a href="pcc2:fleetcost">Fleet Cost comparison</a>,
          and <a href="pcc2:buildship">Ship Building</a> detailed bill.</di>
      </dl>
    </page>

    <!-- Process Manager -->
    <page id="pcc2:processmgr">
      <h1>Process Manager</h1>
      <p>The Process Manager allows you to manage active background scripts such as Auto Tasks.
        When you open this window, you will see all scripts in "Suspended" state, that is, they are not currently running but waiting for something to happen (the next turn, usually).</p>
      <kl>
        <ki key="T">Mark this script for termination. With <kbd>Ctrl</kbd>, mark all scripts for termination;</ki>
        <ki key="R">Mark this script for running. With <kbd>Ctrl</kbd>, mark all scripts for running;</ki>
        <ki key="S">Mark this script to suspend. Use this to undo an accidental <kbd>T</kbd> or <kbd>R</kbd>. With <kbd>Ctrl</kbd>, mark all scripts to suspend;</ki>
        <ki key="X">Execute all terminate/run requests;</ki>
        <ki key="P">Change process priority. Use this to control the order in which scripts run. Lower numerical values means the script runs earlier;</ki>
        <ki key="G">Go to the unit from which this script was started;</ki>
        <ki key="N">If the process has a <a href="pcc2:notify">notification</a>, show it;</ki>
        <ki key="L">If this process holds locks, list them. With <kbd>Ctrl</kbd>, list all locks in the system;</ki>
        <ki key="ESC">Close this window. This will also execute all terminate/run requests.</ki>
      </kl>

      <h2>Columns</h2>

      <dl>
        <di term="Name"> Name of the script;</di>
        <di term="Msg"> Indicates whether the script has a notification;</di>
        <di term="Where"> Indicates the object this script is running on (s111, p111, b111 for ship, planet, base, respectively);</di>
        <di term="Pri"> Priority. Lower numeric values run first;</di>
        <di term="Status"> Target status.
        <dl>
          <di term="Suspended"> Script is waiting and will run automatically next turn;</di>
          <di term="Runnable"> Script was selected to run;</di>
          <di term="Terminated"> Script was selected to be terminated;</di>
          <di term="Frozen"> Auto task is being edited on the auto-task screen and cannot be manipulated here;</di>
          <di term="Waiting"> Script is waiting for user interaction and cannot be manipulated here.
          Because PCC2ng is controlled by scripts, you will see the process that opened the Process Manager in this status.</di>
        </dl></di>
      </dl>

      <h2>Reference</h2>
      <dl>
        <di term="Keys:"> <kbd>Alt-Q</kbd> almost everywhere.</di>
      </dl>
    </page>

    <!-- Help -->
    <page id="help">
      <h1>Help</h1>
      <kl>
        <ki key="&#x2191;, &#x2193;">Scroll;</ki>
        <ki key="PgUp, PgDn">Scroll;</ki>
        <ki key="Tab">Cycle through hyperlinks. With <kbd>Shift</kbd>, cycle backwards;</ki>
        <ki key="Enter">Follow link;</ki>
        <ki key="B, Backspace">Back to previous position (undo follow link);</ki>
        <ki key="G">Go to page. Pages are identified by a name in PCC2 (not a number like in PCC 1.x);</ki>
        <ki key="T">Go to <a href="toc">Table of Content</a>;</ki>
        <ki key="ESC">Exit.</ki>
      </kl>

      <p>PCC2 comes with pre-installed help files regarding usage of PCC2 and the scripting language.
        <a href="pcc2:plugins">Plugins</a> can provide additional help to extend or replace the help texts.
        If the help text you're reading is not the one provided by PCC2, or it is built from multiple pages,
        you will see the source of each text in a small, right-aligned note below the text.</p>

      <h2>Reference</h2>
      <dl>
        <di term="Keys:"> <kbd>Alt-H</kbd> or <kbd>H</kbd> almost everywhere.</di>
      </dl>
    </page>

    <!-- Prefix arg -->
    <page id="prefixarg">
      <h1>Prefix Argument</h1>
      <p>At some places, PCC2 accepts a <em>prefix argument</em> which modifies the following keystroke.
        Normally, this is used to set the amount you wish to build, move, etc.</p>
      <p>To use a prefix argument, just start by typing a number.
        A yellow popup will appear.
        Keep typing, and confirm by pressing the key whose function you want to perform.
        For example, to build 15 factories on the <a href="pcc2:buildings">Buildings</a> screen,
        you'd type <kbd>1</kbd><kbd>5</kbd><kbd>+</kbd>.</p>
      <kl>
        <ki key="Backspace">Delete last digit;</ki>
        <ki key="*">Multiply. Enter <tt>3*3</tt> for a prefix argument of 9;</ki>
        <ki key="&#47;">Divide. Enter <tt>20&#47;4</tt> for a prefix argument of 5;</ki>
        <ki key="ESC">Cancel prefix argument.</ki>
      </kl>
      <p>Note that there is no addition or subtraction operator for the prefix argument.
        Instead, simply use the respective function multiple times.
        To build 10+15 factories, type <kbd>1</kbd><kbd>0</kbd><kbd>+</kbd><kbd>1</kbd><kbd>5</kbd><kbd>+</kbd>.</p>
    </page>
  </page>


  <!-- Configuration -->

  <page id="group:config">
    <h1>Configuration</h1>

    <!-- Intro -->
    <page id="config:intro">
      <h1>Configuration Introduction</h1>
      <p>PCC2 has multiple mechanisms to configure it according to your needs.
        Most of these mechanisms are available on the regular user interface.</p>

      <h2>Where are the configuration files?</h2>

      <p>In Windows, PCC2 creates a directory <tt>PCC2</tt> in your profile directory
        (<tt>C:\Documents and Settings\User\Application Data</tt> or <tt>C:\Users\User\AppData\Roaming</tt>).</p>

      <p>In Unix, PCC2 creates a directory <tt>.pcc2</tt> in your home directory.</p>

      <p>All configuration files will be created in this directory.</p>

      <h2>What configuration files are there?</h2>
      <ul>
        <li><b><a href="config:pcc2ini">pcc2.ini</a>:</b> the main configuration file.
          This file has some special properties described on its <a href="config:pcc2ini">help page</a>;</li>
        <li><b><a href="config:exprini">expr.ini</a>:</b> user-defined search/label expressions;</li>
        <li><b>lru.ini:</b> last search/label expressions.
          This file is automatically updated by PCC2 and has the same format as expr.ini;</li>
        <li><b>plugins/:</b> this folder contains <a href="pcc2:plugins">plugins</a>.</li>
      </ul>

      <h2>Legacy configuration</h2>
      <ul>
        <li><b><a href="config:ccres">cc-res.cfg</a>:</b> this file is located in the resource directory of your PCC2 directory
          and can be used to configure resources (images).
          This is used by the installer.
          Normally, you should install an artwork plugin instead;</li>
        <li>PCC2 comes with a standard ship list which is stored in <tt>C:\Programs\PCC2\share\specs</tt> or <tt>/opt/c2ng/share/specs</tt>.
          In addition to standard files like <tt>hullspec.dat</tt>, this directory also contains a few PCC-specific files ending in <tt>.cc</tt>.
          These can be overridden on a per-game basis by placing an identically-named file in your game directory,
          in the same way non-standard ship lists can be used.
          It is not recommended to ever modify the files in PCC2's ship list directory.<br/>
          In addition, you can create a file ending with <tt>.usr</tt> in your game directory.
          That file will behave as if it were appended to the respective <tt>.cc</tt> file.</li>
      </ul>
    </page>

    <!-- pcc2.ini -->
    <page id="config:pcc2ini">
      <h1>pcc2.ini</h1>
      <p>This is the main configuration file.</p>
      <p><tt>pcc2.ini</tt> will be created in your profile directory.
        Previous versions of PCC2 placed this file directly in your home directory.
        If it is already there, it will stay there.
        However, new files will be created in the configuration directory.</p>

      <p>In addition, PCC2 supports per-game configuration.
        A <tt>pcc2.ini</tt> file can also exist in a game directory;
        settings from that file override those in the main configuration file.</p>

      <p>Dialogs like the <a href="pcc2:settings">settings dialog</a> will offer you choice
        whether a setting is stored in the main ("User") or game configuration file.</p>

      <h2>Reference</h2>
      <dl>
        <di term="See also:"> <a href="config:intro">Configuration Introduction</a>, <a href="pcc2:settings">settings dialog"</a>,
          <a href="pcc2:starchartopts">starchart configuration dialog</a>.</di>
      </dl>
    </page>

    <!-- expr.ini -->
    <page id="config:exprini">
      <h1>expr.ini</h1>
      <p>This file allows you to configure expressions for the <a href="pcc2:search">search function</a> and <a href="pcc2:labels">unit labels</a>.
        Those expressions will then be available for easy selection using a drop-down menu.</p>

      <p>PCC2 comes with predefined expressions in a file <tt>expr.cc</tt> that is located in PCC2's main specification directory.
        It is not recommended to edit <tt>expr.cc</tt>; instead, create <tt>expr.ini</tt>. Both files have the same syntax.</p>

      <p>A new section starts with a section name in brackets:</p>
      <ul class="compact">
        <li><tt>[Find]</tt>: search expressions;</li>
        <li><tt>[ShipLabels]</tt>: ship labels;</li>
        <li><tt>[PlanetLabels]</tt>: planet labels.</li>
      </ul>

      <p>Within each section, each expression is defined with a line like this:</p>
      <pre>Name of Expression   [p] Expression+here</pre>

      <ul class="compact">
        <li>Name that is shown in drop-down lists;</li>
        <li>Two spaces as separator;</li>
        <li>For search expressions, the object type in parentheses: [p]=planets, [s]=ships, [b]=bases.
          Combinations like [sp]=ships and planets are allowed;</li>
        <li>Finally, the actual <a href="int:expr">expression</a>.</li>
      </ul>

      <h2>Reference</h2>
      <dl>
        <di term="See also:"> <a href="config:intro">Configuration Introduction</a>.</di>
      </dl>
    </page>

    <!-- cc-res.cfg -->
    <page id="config:ccres">
      <h1>cc-res.cfg</h1>
      <p>This file defines additional resource files to load.
        It is located in the resource directory of your PCC2 directory
        (<tt>C:\Programs\PCC2\share\resource</tt> in Windows, <tt>/opt/c2ng/share/resource</tt> in Unix).
        Typically, it does not exist and you must create it as a text file.
        This file can be used to configure resources (images).</p>

      <p>Each line contains one link to a resource package.
        Empty lines and lines starting with ";" are ignored.</p>

      <ul>
        <li><tt>res:<b>file.res</b></tt><br/><b>file.res</b> is the name of a PCC 1.x resource file which is used to provide ship, base, planet, and fighter images;</li>
        <li><tt>wp:<b>dir</b></tt><br/><b>dir</b> points at a Winplan "bmp" directory which provides ship images;</li>
        <li><tt>wpvcr:<b>file.dll</b></tt><br/><b>file.dll</b> is the name of a Winplan "wpvcr.dll" file which provides ship images for the VCR;</li>
        <li><tt>dir:<b>dir</b></tt><br/><b>dir</b> points at a PCC2 resource directory.</li>
      </ul>

      <p>A line that does not match any of these formats is treated as the name of a PCC 1.x resource file (as in PCC 1.x).</p>

      <h2>Reference</h2>
      <dl>
        <di term="See also:"> <a href="config:intro">Configuration Introduction</a>.</di>
      </dl>
    </page>
  </page>
</help>
